<bill session="114" type="h" number="1416" updated="2015-05-09T06:33:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cancer Patient Protection Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent application of sequestration to payment for certain physician-administered drugs under part B of the Medicare program in fiscal years 2016 and 2017, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400032" joined="2015-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412196" joined="2015-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2015--Introduced.
Cancer Patient Protection Act of 2015

This bill requires any new presidential sequestration order for FY2016-FY2017 to declare that no reduction shall be made with respect to payments for physician-administered drugs and biologicals under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to the extent that such payments are made based on their average sales price.

The Government Accountability Office must examine the shift of cancer care from physician-run community cancer clinics to hospitals and its consequences to costs to the federal government and to Medicare beneficiaries for cancer care under the Medicare program.</summary>
</bill>
