<bill session="114" type="h" number="1525" updated="2015-05-22T04:48:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to make certain improvements to form 10-K and regulation S-K, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 60 - 0.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="37"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/2015--Introduced.
Disclosure Modernization and Simplification Act of 2015

 Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to issue regulations permitting issuers to submit a summary page on annual and transition report form 10-K if each item on that page cross-references electronically or otherwise the material contained in form 10-K to which the item relates.

Requires the SEC to revise regulation S-K (Standard Instructions for Filing Forms under the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Energy Policy and Conservation Act of 1975) in order to:

 reduce the burden on smaller issuers, including emerging growth companies, accelerated filers, and smaller reporting companies (while still providing all material information to investors); eliminate duplicative, overlapping, outdated, or unnecessary provisions; and for which the SEC determines no further study under this Act is necessary to determine the efficacy of such revisions. Directs the SEC to study ways to: (1) modernize and simplify requirements in regulation S-K, and (2) evaluate information delivery and presentation methods as well as explore methods to discourage repetition and disclosure of immaterial information.

Requires the SEC to issue a proposed rule to implement any recommendations it makes to Congress based upon the study.</summary>
</bill>
