<bill session="114" type="h" number="1590" updated="2015-06-12T04:52:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a prize program to award a prize and contract for the development of a fully-integrated electronic health records program for use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400068" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR08" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/2015--Introduced.
Integrated Electronic Health Records (iEHR) for Military and Veterans Act - Directs the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA) to jointly carry out a program to award a cash prize ($50 million) and contract to an entity that develops a fully-integrated electronic health records program for national use by DOD and VA. Directs the Secretaries to: (1) widely advertise the prize competitions and announce each one in the Federal Register, and (2) create a joint panel to establish criteria for the program's development.

 Requires the prize recipient to be awarded a contract with DOD and VA to provide the program, including maintenance and support, and to be compensated at $25 million per year for five years. Reverts to the federal government, after such period, any intellectual property developed under the contract.

Authorizes the Secretaries to require competition participants to waive claims against the federal government (except for willful conduct) arising from such participation. Requires participants to obtain liability insurance.</summary>
</bill>
