<bill session="114" type="h" number="1710" updated="2015-06-27T06:47:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drought Resilience Investment Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 to provide additional financing options for water infrastructure projects carried out in States in which the Governor of the State has issued a state of drought emergency declaration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2015-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412511" joined="2015-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400663" joined="2015-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and the Economy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF18" subcommittee="Environment and the Economy" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2015--Introduced.
Drought Resilience Investment Act of 2015

Amends the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 to exempt a water resources infrastructure project receiving federal credit assistance under the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act, that is carried out in a state during any period in which a state of drought declaration issued by the state's governor is in effect, from the prohibition against being financed with proceeds of any: (1) obligation that is tax exempt; or (2) qualified tax credit bond or a Build America Bond.

Specifies that a state of drought declaration shall remain in effect until the date on which the governor rescinds the declaration.

Terminates this Act on September 30, 2018.</summary>
</bill>
