<bill session="114" type="h" number="1735" updated="2015-08-22T06:33:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-18">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">An act to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400379" joined="2015-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Tactical Air and Land Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 60 - 2.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-05T11:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 114-102.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-05T11:45:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="71">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 71.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12T19:43:00-04:00">
      <text>SUPPLEMENTAL FILING AUTHORITY - Mr. Thornberry asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to file a supplemental report on the bill, H.R. 1735. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12T20:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 114-102, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-12T22:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 255 Reported to House. Providing for consideration of H.R. 1735, H.R. 36, and H.R. 2048</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 255.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2940-2948" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 255 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Garret Graves to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1735.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T18:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to section 1 of H.Res. 255, the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1735 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13T23:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 260 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1735. Specified amendments are in order. Providing for amendment debate for H.R. 1735</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:01:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 260 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2999-3181" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2999-3153" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1735. Specified amendments are in order. Providing for amendment debate for H.R. 1735</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:21:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 260 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thornberry amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:39:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Forbes demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T16:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry en bloc amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brooks (AL) amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brooks (AL) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walorski amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:34:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Walorski amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Walorski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T17:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCaul amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCaul amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. O'Rourke demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hunter amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T18:11:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry en bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1735 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3181-3206" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rohrabacher amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:35:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rohrabacher amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rohrabacher demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:36:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:47:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lamborn amendment No. 27, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cooper demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T19:48:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:00:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 32, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Forbes demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lummis amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry amendments en bloc #3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:24:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lucas amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lucas amendment No. 38, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Langevin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:50:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nadler amendment No. 41, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T20:58:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry amendments en bloc #4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry amendments en bloc #5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T21:17:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 83.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T21:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14T21:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1735 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T09:06:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3219-3236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T09:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T09:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry en bloc amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T09:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry en bloc amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T09:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 260, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry en bloc amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1735.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3233" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3233" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gallego moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3233-3236" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3233" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gallego motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to provide a 2.3% pay increase for fiscal year 2016 for members of the uniformed services. Additionally, the motion would ensure that the Secretary of Defense guarantee members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps continue to receive compensation for their service in defense of the United States despite any government shutdown after September 30, 2015.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:48:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3234" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T10:55:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 234 (Roll no. 238).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3234-3235" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="239" datetime="2015-05-15T11:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 269 - 151 (Roll no. 239).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15T11:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1735.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3236" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="99">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 99.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-31">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3371" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-31">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3341" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3341" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3442" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3642-3654, S3654-3667" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-04">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3734-3758" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-08">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3850-3855" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-09">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3898-3905, S3905-3921" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3986-4017, S4017-4018" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4073-4090, S4090-4091, S4095-4097" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4187" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4187" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4173-4185, S4185-4194, S4195" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4222-4247" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="214" datetime="2015-06-17" where="s" result="pass">
      <text>Cloture invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 84 - 14. Record Vote Number: 214.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4247" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4247" label="text"/>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4258-4275" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="215" datetime="2015-06-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 71 - 25. Record Vote Number: 215.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/22/2015 S4358-4521" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-18">
      <text>Senate ordered measure printed as passed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T09:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 340, papers are returned to the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Message received in Senate: Returned to the Senate pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 340.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Section 636 was stricken by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4620-4621" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4699" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4699" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Armed Services for consideration of the House bill and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Thornberry, Forbes, Miller (FL), Wilson (SC), LoBiondo, Bishop (UT), Turner, Kline, Rogers (AL), Shuster, Conaway, Lamborn, Wittman, Hunter, Hartzler, Heck (NV), Wenstrup, Stefanik, Smith (WA), Sanchez, Loretta, Davis (CA), Langevin, Larsen (WA), Cooper, Bordallo, Courtney, Tsongas, Garamendi, Johnson (GA), Speier, Castro (TX), and Duckworth .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25T12:52:00-04:00">
      <text>FURTHER APPOINTMENTS OF CONFEREES - The Chair announced that further appointments of conferees would occur at a subsequent time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the House authorize conferees to close meetings.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4814-4815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to authorize conferees to close meetings Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 402 - 12 (Roll no. 390).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-07T18:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4915-4920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Motion to insist on Senate amendment, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to insist on Senate amendment, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4915" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4915" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to insist on Senate amendment, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 81 - 15. Record Vote Number: 229.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Motion to insist on Senate amendment, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, agrees to request for conference, and authorizes the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4919" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reed to instruct Senate conferees made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4919-4920" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4919" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reed to instruct Senate conferees (OCO) rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 44 - 52. Record Vote Number: 230.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees McCain, Inhofe, Sessions, Wicker, Ayotte, Fischer, Cotton, Rounds, Graham, Reed, Nelson, Manchin, Gillibrand, Donnelly, Hirono, Kaine.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4920" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T11:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, for consideration of matters within the jurisdiction of that committee under clause 11 of rule X: Nunes, King (NY), and Schiff.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for consideration of secs. 571 and 573 of the House bill and secs. 561-63 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Rokita, Bishop (MI), and Scott (VA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for consideration of secs. 314, 632, 634, 3111-13, 3119, 3133, and 3141 of the House bill and secs. 601, 632, 3118, and 3119 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Upton, Barton, and Pallone.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for consideration of secs. 1011, 1059, 1090, 1092, 1201, 1203-05, 1215, 1221, 1223, 1226, 1234-36, 1247-49, 1253, 1257, 1263, 1264, 1267, 1270, 1301, 1532, 1541, 1542, 1663, 1668-70, 2802, 3118, and 3119 of the House bill and secs. 1011, 1012, 1082, 1201-05, 1207, 1209, 1223, 1225, 1228, 1251, 1252, 1261, 1264, 1265, 1272, 1301, 1302, 1531-33, 1631, 1654, and 1655 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Royce, Marino, and Engel.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Homeland Security, for consideration of secs. 589 and 1041 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: McCaul, Miller (MI), and Thompson (MS).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on the Judiciary, for consideration of secs. 1040, 1052, 1085, 1216, 1641, and 2862 of the House bill and secs. 1032, 1034, 1090, and 1227 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Goodlatte, Issa, and Conyers.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Natural Resources, for consideration of secs. 312, 632, 634, 2841, 2842, 2851-53, and 2862 of the House bill and secs. 313, 601, and 632 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Cook, Hardy, and Grijalva.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for consideration of secs. 602, 631, 634, 838, 854, 855, 866, 871, 1069, and 1101-05 of the House bill and secs. 592, 593, 631, 806, 830, 861, 1090, 1101, 1102, 1104, 1105, 1107-09, 1111, 1112, 1114, and 1115 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Hurd (TX), Russell, and Cummings.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:01:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Rules, for consideration of sec. 1032 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Sessions, Byrne, and Slaughter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for consideration of sec. 3136 of the House bill and sec. 1613 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Lucas, Knight, and Johnson, E. B..</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Small Business, for consideration of secs. 831-34, 839, 840, 842-46, 854, and 871 of the House bill and secs. 828, 831, 882, 883, and 885 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Chabot, Hanna, and Velazquez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for consideration of secs. 302, 562, 569, 570a, 591, 1060a, 1073, 2811, and 3501 of the House bill and secs. 601, 642, 1613, 3504, and 3505 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Graves (LA), Curbelo (FL), and Edwards.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-10T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees from the Committee on Veterans Affairs, for consideration of secs. 565, 566, 592, 652, 701, 721, 722, 1105, and 1431 of the House bill and secs. 539, 605, 633, 719, 1083, 1084, 1089, 1091, and 1411 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Roe (TN), Bilirakis, and Brown (FL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5086" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS26" subcommittee="Emerging Threats and Capabilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS25" subcommittee="Tactical Air and Land Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS28" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS29" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="hr" number="179"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="hr" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="114" type="hr" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="114" type="hr" number="255"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="114" type="hr" number="260"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="hr" number="340"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="hr" number="340"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="135"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="147"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="838"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="955"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1227"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1337"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1349"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1384"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1386"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1390"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1410"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1451"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1583"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1597"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1864"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2026"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2055"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2133"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2294"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2747"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="743"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="958"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1118"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1266"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1292"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1376"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1437"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Bahrain"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Portugal"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Qatar"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h216"/>
    <amendment number="h217"/>
    <amendment number="h218"/>
    <amendment number="h219"/>
    <amendment number="h220"/>
    <amendment number="h221"/>
    <amendment number="h222"/>
    <amendment number="h223"/>
    <amendment number="h224"/>
    <amendment number="h225"/>
    <amendment number="h226"/>
    <amendment number="h227"/>
    <amendment number="h228"/>
    <amendment number="h229"/>
    <amendment number="h230"/>
    <amendment number="h231"/>
    <amendment number="h232"/>
    <amendment number="h233"/>
    <amendment number="h234"/>
    <amendment number="h235"/>
    <amendment number="h236"/>
    <amendment number="h237"/>
    <amendment number="h238"/>
    <amendment number="s1456"/>
    <amendment number="s1461"/>
    <amendment number="s1462"/>
    <amendment number="s1463"/>
    <amendment number="s1464"/>
    <amendment number="s1465"/>
    <amendment number="s1466"/>
    <amendment number="s1467"/>
    <amendment number="s1468"/>
    <amendment number="s1469"/>
    <amendment number="s1470"/>
    <amendment number="s1472"/>
    <amendment number="s1473"/>
    <amendment number="s1474"/>
    <amendment number="s1475"/>
    <amendment number="s1476"/>
    <amendment number="s1477"/>
    <amendment number="s1478"/>
    <amendment number="s1479"/>
    <amendment number="s1480"/>
    <amendment number="s1481"/>
    <amendment number="s1482"/>
    <amendment number="s1483"/>
    <amendment number="s1484"/>
    <amendment number="s1485"/>
    <amendment number="s1486"/>
    <amendment number="s1487"/>
    <amendment number="s1488"/>
    <amendment number="s1489"/>
    <amendment number="s1490"/>
    <amendment number="s1491"/>
    <amendment number="s1492"/>
    <amendment number="s1493"/>
    <amendment number="s1494"/>
    <amendment number="s1495"/>
    <amendment number="s1496"/>
    <amendment number="s1497"/>
    <amendment number="s1498"/>
    <amendment number="s1499"/>
    <amendment number="s1500"/>
    <amendment number="s1501"/>
    <amendment number="s1502"/>
    <amendment number="s1503"/>
    <amendment number="s1504"/>
    <amendment number="s1505"/>
    <amendment number="s1506"/>
    <amendment number="s1507"/>
    <amendment number="s1508"/>
    <amendment number="s1509"/>
    <amendment number="s1510"/>
    <amendment number="s1511"/>
    <amendment number="s1512"/>
    <amendment number="s1513"/>
    <amendment number="s1514"/>
    <amendment number="s1515"/>
    <amendment number="s1516"/>
    <amendment number="s1517"/>
    <amendment number="s1518"/>
    <amendment number="s1519"/>
    <amendment number="s1520"/>
    <amendment number="s1521"/>
    <amendment number="s1522"/>
    <amendment number="s1523"/>
    <amendment number="s1524"/>
    <amendment number="s1525"/>
    <amendment number="s1526"/>
    <amendment number="s1527"/>
    <amendment number="s1528"/>
    <amendment number="s1529"/>
    <amendment number="s1530"/>
    <amendment number="s1531"/>
    <amendment number="s1532"/>
    <amendment number="s1533"/>
    <amendment number="s1534"/>
    <amendment number="s1535"/>
    <amendment number="s1536"/>
    <amendment number="s1537"/>
    <amendment number="s1538"/>
    <amendment number="s1539"/>
    <amendment number="s1540"/>
    <amendment number="s1541"/>
    <amendment number="s1542"/>
    <amendment number="s1543"/>
    <amendment number="s1544"/>
    <amendment number="s1545"/>
    <amendment number="s1546"/>
    <amendment number="s1547"/>
    <amendment number="s1548"/>
    <amendment number="s1549"/>
    <amendment number="s1550"/>
    <amendment number="s1551"/>
    <amendment number="s1552"/>
    <amendment number="s1553"/>
    <amendment number="s1554"/>
    <amendment number="s1555"/>
    <amendment number="s1556"/>
    <amendment number="s1557"/>
    <amendment number="s1558"/>
    <amendment number="s1559"/>
    <amendment number="s1560"/>
    <amendment number="s1561"/>
    <amendment number="s1562"/>
    <amendment number="s1563"/>
    <amendment number="s1564"/>
    <amendment number="s1565"/>
    <amendment number="s1566"/>
    <amendment number="s1567"/>
    <amendment number="s1568"/>
    <amendment number="s1569"/>
    <amendment number="s1570"/>
    <amendment number="s1571"/>
    <amendment number="s1572"/>
    <amendment number="s1573"/>
    <amendment number="s1574"/>
    <amendment number="s1575"/>
    <amendment number="s1576"/>
    <amendment number="s1577"/>
    <amendment number="s1578"/>
    <amendment number="s1579"/>
    <amendment number="s1580"/>
    <amendment number="s1581"/>
    <amendment number="s1582"/>
    <amendment number="s1583"/>
    <amendment number="s1584"/>
    <amendment number="s1585"/>
    <amendment number="s1586"/>
    <amendment number="s1587"/>
    <amendment number="s1588"/>
    <amendment number="s1589"/>
    <amendment number="s1590"/>
    <amendment number="s1591"/>
    <amendment number="s1592"/>
    <amendment number="s1593"/>
    <amendment number="s1594"/>
    <amendment number="s1595"/>
    <amendment number="s1596"/>
    <amendment number="s1597"/>
    <amendment number="s1598"/>
    <amendment number="s1599"/>
    <amendment number="s1600"/>
    <amendment number="s1601"/>
    <amendment number="s1602"/>
    <amendment number="s1603"/>
    <amendment number="s1604"/>
    <amendment number="s1605"/>
    <amendment number="s1606"/>
    <amendment number="s1607"/>
    <amendment number="s1608"/>
    <amendment number="s1609"/>
    <amendment number="s1610"/>
    <amendment number="s1611"/>
    <amendment number="s1612"/>
    <amendment number="s1613"/>
    <amendment number="s1614"/>
    <amendment number="s1615"/>
    <amendment number="s1616"/>
    <amendment number="s1617"/>
    <amendment number="s1618"/>
    <amendment number="s1619"/>
    <amendment number="s1620"/>
    <amendment number="s1621"/>
    <amendment number="s1622"/>
    <amendment number="s1623"/>
    <amendment number="s1624"/>
    <amendment number="s1625"/>
    <amendment number="s1626"/>
    <amendment number="s1627"/>
    <amendment number="s1628"/>
    <amendment number="s1629"/>
    <amendment number="s1630"/>
    <amendment number="s1631"/>
    <amendment number="s1632"/>
    <amendment number="s1633"/>
    <amendment number="s1634"/>
    <amendment number="s1635"/>
    <amendment number="s1636"/>
    <amendment number="s1637"/>
    <amendment number="s1638"/>
    <amendment number="s1639"/>
    <amendment number="s1640"/>
    <amendment number="s1641"/>
    <amendment number="s1642"/>
    <amendment number="s1643"/>
    <amendment number="s1644"/>
    <amendment number="s1645"/>
    <amendment number="s1646"/>
    <amendment number="s1647"/>
    <amendment number="s1648"/>
    <amendment number="s1649"/>
    <amendment number="s1650"/>
    <amendment number="s1651"/>
    <amendment number="s1652"/>
    <amendment number="s1653"/>
    <amendment number="s1654"/>
    <amendment number="s1655"/>
    <amendment number="s1656"/>
    <amendment number="s1657"/>
    <amendment number="s1658"/>
    <amendment number="s1659"/>
    <amendment number="s1660"/>
    <amendment number="s1661"/>
    <amendment number="s1662"/>
    <amendment number="s1663"/>
    <amendment number="s1664"/>
    <amendment number="s1665"/>
    <amendment number="s1666"/>
    <amendment number="s1667"/>
    <amendment number="s1668"/>
    <amendment number="s1669"/>
    <amendment number="s1670"/>
    <amendment number="s1671"/>
    <amendment number="s1672"/>
    <amendment number="s1673"/>
    <amendment number="s1674"/>
    <amendment number="s1675"/>
    <amendment number="s1676"/>
    <amendment number="s1677"/>
    <amendment number="s1678"/>
    <amendment number="s1679"/>
    <amendment number="s1680"/>
    <amendment number="s1681"/>
    <amendment number="s1682"/>
    <amendment number="s1683"/>
    <amendment number="s1684"/>
    <amendment number="s1685"/>
    <amendment number="s1686"/>
    <amendment number="s1687"/>
    <amendment number="s1688"/>
    <amendment number="s1689"/>
    <amendment number="s1690"/>
    <amendment number="s1691"/>
    <amendment number="s1692"/>
    <amendment number="s1693"/>
    <amendment number="s1694"/>
    <amendment number="s1695"/>
    <amendment number="s1696"/>
    <amendment number="s1697"/>
    <amendment number="s1698"/>
    <amendment number="s1699"/>
    <amendment number="s1700"/>
    <amendment number="s1701"/>
    <amendment number="s1702"/>
    <amendment number="s1703"/>
    <amendment number="s1704"/>
    <amendment number="s1705"/>
    <amendment number="s1706"/>
    <amendment number="s1707"/>
    <amendment number="s1708"/>
    <amendment number="s1709"/>
    <amendment number="s1710"/>
    <amendment number="s1711"/>
    <amendment number="s1712"/>
    <amendment number="s1713"/>
    <amendment number="s1714"/>
    <amendment number="s1715"/>
    <amendment number="s1716"/>
    <amendment number="s1717"/>
    <amendment number="s1718"/>
    <amendment number="s1719"/>
    <amendment number="s1720"/>
    <amendment number="s1721"/>
    <amendment number="s1722"/>
    <amendment number="s1723"/>
    <amendment number="s1724"/>
    <amendment number="s1725"/>
    <amendment number="s1726"/>
    <amendment number="s1727"/>
    <amendment number="s1728"/>
    <amendment number="s1729"/>
    <amendment number="s1730"/>
    <amendment number="s1731"/>
    <amendment number="s1732"/>
    <amendment number="s1733"/>
    <amendment number="s1734"/>
    <amendment number="s1735"/>
    <amendment number="s1736"/>
    <amendment number="s1737"/>
    <amendment number="s1738"/>
    <amendment number="s1739"/>
    <amendment number="s1740"/>
    <amendment number="s1741"/>
    <amendment number="s1742"/>
    <amendment number="s1743"/>
    <amendment number="s1744"/>
    <amendment number="s1745"/>
    <amendment number="s1746"/>
    <amendment number="s1747"/>
    <amendment number="s1748"/>
    <amendment number="s1749"/>
    <amendment number="s1750"/>
    <amendment number="s1751"/>
    <amendment number="s1752"/>
    <amendment number="s1753"/>
    <amendment number="s1754"/>
    <amendment number="s1755"/>
    <amendment number="s1756"/>
    <amendment number="s1757"/>
    <amendment number="s1758"/>
    <amendment number="s1759"/>
    <amendment number="s1760"/>
    <amendment number="s1761"/>
    <amendment number="s1762"/>
    <amendment number="s1763"/>
    <amendment number="s1764"/>
    <amendment number="s1765"/>
    <amendment number="s1766"/>
    <amendment number="s1767"/>
    <amendment number="s1768"/>
    <amendment number="s1769"/>
    <amendment number="s1770"/>
    <amendment number="s1771"/>
    <amendment number="s1772"/>
    <amendment number="s1773"/>
    <amendment number="s1774"/>
    <amendment number="s1775"/>
    <amendment number="s1776"/>
    <amendment number="s1777"/>
    <amendment number="s1778"/>
    <amendment number="s1779"/>
    <amendment number="s1780"/>
    <amendment number="s1781"/>
    <amendment number="s1783"/>
    <amendment number="s1784"/>
    <amendment number="s1785"/>
    <amendment number="s1786"/>
    <amendment number="s1787"/>
    <amendment number="s1788"/>
    <amendment number="s1789"/>
    <amendment number="s1790"/>
    <amendment number="s1791"/>
    <amendment number="s1792"/>
    <amendment number="s1793"/>
    <amendment number="s1794"/>
    <amendment number="s1795"/>
    <amendment number="s1796"/>
    <amendment number="s1797"/>
    <amendment number="s1798"/>
    <amendment number="s1799"/>
    <amendment number="s1800"/>
    <amendment number="s1801"/>
    <amendment number="s1802"/>
    <amendment number="s1803"/>
    <amendment number="s1804"/>
    <amendment number="s1805"/>
    <amendment number="s1806"/>
    <amendment number="s1807"/>
    <amendment number="s1808"/>
    <amendment number="s1809"/>
    <amendment number="s1810"/>
    <amendment number="s1811"/>
    <amendment number="s1812"/>
    <amendment number="s1813"/>
    <amendment number="s1814"/>
    <amendment number="s1815"/>
    <amendment number="s1816"/>
    <amendment number="s1817"/>
    <amendment number="s1818"/>
    <amendment number="s1819"/>
    <amendment number="s1820"/>
    <amendment number="s1821"/>
    <amendment number="s1822"/>
    <amendment number="s1823"/>
    <amendment number="s1824"/>
    <amendment number="s1825"/>
    <amendment number="s1826"/>
    <amendment number="s1827"/>
    <amendment number="s1828"/>
    <amendment number="s1829"/>
    <amendment number="s1830"/>
    <amendment number="s1831"/>
    <amendment number="s1832"/>
    <amendment number="s1833"/>
    <amendment number="s1834"/>
    <amendment number="s1835"/>
    <amendment number="s1836"/>
    <amendment number="s1837"/>
    <amendment number="s1838"/>
    <amendment number="s1839"/>
    <amendment number="s1840"/>
    <amendment number="s1841"/>
    <amendment number="s1842"/>
    <amendment number="s1843"/>
    <amendment number="s1844"/>
    <amendment number="s1845"/>
    <amendment number="s1846"/>
    <amendment number="s1847"/>
    <amendment number="s1848"/>
    <amendment number="s1849"/>
    <amendment number="s1850"/>
    <amendment number="s1851"/>
    <amendment number="s1852"/>
    <amendment number="s1853"/>
    <amendment number="s1854"/>
    <amendment number="s1855"/>
    <amendment number="s1856"/>
    <amendment number="s1857"/>
    <amendment number="s1858"/>
    <amendment number="s1859"/>
    <amendment number="s1860"/>
    <amendment number="s1861"/>
    <amendment number="s1862"/>
    <amendment number="s1863"/>
    <amendment number="s1864"/>
    <amendment number="s1865"/>
    <amendment number="s1866"/>
    <amendment number="s1867"/>
    <amendment number="s1868"/>
    <amendment number="s1869"/>
    <amendment number="s1870"/>
    <amendment number="s1871"/>
    <amendment number="s1872"/>
    <amendment number="s1873"/>
    <amendment number="s1874"/>
    <amendment number="s1875"/>
    <amendment number="s1876"/>
    <amendment number="s1877"/>
    <amendment number="s1878"/>
    <amendment number="s1879"/>
    <amendment number="s1880"/>
    <amendment number="s1881"/>
    <amendment number="s1882"/>
    <amendment number="s1883"/>
    <amendment number="s1884"/>
    <amendment number="s1885"/>
    <amendment number="s1886"/>
    <amendment number="s1887"/>
    <amendment number="s1888"/>
    <amendment number="s1889"/>
    <amendment number="s1890"/>
    <amendment number="s1891"/>
    <amendment number="s1892"/>
    <amendment number="s1893"/>
    <amendment number="s1894"/>
    <amendment number="s1895"/>
    <amendment number="s1896"/>
    <amendment number="s1897"/>
    <amendment number="s1898"/>
    <amendment number="s1899"/>
    <amendment number="s1900"/>
    <amendment number="s1901"/>
    <amendment number="s1902"/>
    <amendment number="s1903"/>
    <amendment number="s1904"/>
    <amendment number="s1905"/>
    <amendment number="s1906"/>
    <amendment number="s1907"/>
    <amendment number="s1908"/>
    <amendment number="s1909"/>
    <amendment number="s1910"/>
    <amendment number="s1911"/>
    <amendment number="s1912"/>
    <amendment number="s1913"/>
    <amendment number="s1914"/>
    <amendment number="s1915"/>
    <amendment number="s1916"/>
    <amendment number="s1917"/>
    <amendment number="s1918"/>
    <amendment number="s1919"/>
    <amendment number="s1920"/>
    <amendment number="s1921"/>
    <amendment number="s1922"/>
    <amendment number="s1923"/>
    <amendment number="s1924"/>
    <amendment number="s1925"/>
    <amendment number="s1926"/>
    <amendment number="s1927"/>
    <amendment number="s1928"/>
    <amendment number="s1929"/>
    <amendment number="s1930"/>
    <amendment number="s1931"/>
    <amendment number="s1932"/>
    <amendment number="s1933"/>
    <amendment number="s1934"/>
    <amendment number="s1935"/>
    <amendment number="s1936"/>
    <amendment number="s1937"/>
    <amendment number="s1938"/>
    <amendment number="s1939"/>
    <amendment number="s1940"/>
    <amendment number="s1941"/>
    <amendment number="s1942"/>
    <amendment number="s1943"/>
    <amendment number="s1944"/>
    <amendment number="s1945"/>
    <amendment number="s1946"/>
    <amendment number="s1947"/>
    <amendment number="s1948"/>
    <amendment number="s1949"/>
    <amendment number="s1950"/>
    <amendment number="s1951"/>
    <amendment number="s1952"/>
    <amendment number="s1953"/>
    <amendment number="s1954"/>
    <amendment number="s1955"/>
    <amendment number="s1956"/>
    <amendment number="s1957"/>
    <amendment number="s1958"/>
    <amendment number="s1959"/>
    <amendment number="s1960"/>
    <amendment number="s1961"/>
    <amendment number="s1962"/>
    <amendment number="s1963"/>
    <amendment number="s1964"/>
    <amendment number="s1965"/>
    <amendment number="s1966"/>
    <amendment number="s1967"/>
    <amendment number="s1968"/>
    <amendment number="s1969"/>
    <amendment number="s1970"/>
    <amendment number="s1971"/>
    <amendment number="s1972"/>
    <amendment number="s1973"/>
    <amendment number="s1974"/>
    <amendment number="s1975"/>
    <amendment number="s1976"/>
    <amendment number="s1977"/>
    <amendment number="s1978"/>
    <amendment number="s1979"/>
    <amendment number="s1980"/>
    <amendment number="s1981"/>
    <amendment number="s1982"/>
    <amendment number="s1983"/>
    <amendment number="s1984"/>
    <amendment number="s1985"/>
    <amendment number="s1986"/>
    <amendment number="s1987"/>
    <amendment number="s1988"/>
    <amendment number="s1989"/>
    <amendment number="s1990"/>
    <amendment number="s1991"/>
    <amendment number="s1992"/>
    <amendment number="s1993"/>
    <amendment number="s1994"/>
    <amendment number="s1995"/>
    <amendment number="s1996"/>
    <amendment number="s1997"/>
    <amendment number="s1998"/>
    <amendment number="s1999"/>
    <amendment number="s2000"/>
    <amendment number="s2001"/>
    <amendment number="s2002"/>
    <amendment number="s2003"/>
    <amendment number="s2004"/>
    <amendment number="s2005"/>
    <amendment number="s2006"/>
    <amendment number="s2007"/>
    <amendment number="s2008"/>
    <amendment number="s2009"/>
    <amendment number="s2010"/>
    <amendment number="s2011"/>
    <amendment number="s2012"/>
    <amendment number="s2013"/>
    <amendment number="s2014"/>
    <amendment number="s2015"/>
    <amendment number="s2016"/>
    <amendment number="s2017"/>
    <amendment number="s2018"/>
    <amendment number="s2019"/>
    <amendment number="s2020"/>
    <amendment number="s2021"/>
    <amendment number="s2022"/>
    <amendment number="s2023"/>
    <amendment number="s2024"/>
    <amendment number="s2025"/>
    <amendment number="s2026"/>
    <amendment number="s2027"/>
    <amendment number="s2028"/>
    <amendment number="s2029"/>
    <amendment number="s2030"/>
    <amendment number="s2031"/>
    <amendment number="s2032"/>
    <amendment number="s2033"/>
    <amendment number="s2034"/>
    <amendment number="s2035"/>
    <amendment number="s2036"/>
    <amendment number="s2037"/>
    <amendment number="s2038"/>
    <amendment number="s2039"/>
    <amendment number="s2040"/>
    <amendment number="s2041"/>
    <amendment number="s2042"/>
    <amendment number="s2043"/>
    <amendment number="s2044"/>
    <amendment number="s2045"/>
    <amendment number="s2046"/>
    <amendment number="s2047"/>
    <amendment number="s2048"/>
    <amendment number="s2049"/>
    <amendment number="s2050"/>
    <amendment number="s2051"/>
    <amendment number="s2052"/>
    <amendment number="s2053"/>
    <amendment number="s2054"/>
    <amendment number="s2055"/>
    <amendment number="s2056"/>
    <amendment number="s2057"/>
    <amendment number="s2058"/>
    <amendment number="s2059"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/15/2015--Passed House amended.
Highlights: 

The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 authorizes FY2016 appropriations and sets forth policies regarding the military activities of the Department of Defense (DOD), military construction, and the national security programs of the Department of Energy (DOE). The bill authorizes appropriations, but does not provide appropriations, which are considered in subsequent appropriations legislation.

The bill authorizes appropriations to DOD for:

 Procurement; Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation; Operation and Maintenance; Cooperative Threat Reduction; Working Capital Funds; the National Defense Sealift Fund; Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction; Defense-Wide Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities; the Defense Inspector General; and the Defense Health Program. This bill also authorizes appropriations for Overseas Contingency Operations (OCO), which are exempt from limits on discretionary spending. OCO appropriations authorized in the bill support base budget requirements as well as OCO activities.

The bill authorizes the FY2016 personnel strengths for active duty and reserve forces and sets forth policies regarding military personnel; compensation and other personnel benefits; health care; acquisition policy and management; DOD organization and management; civilian personnel matters; matters relating to foreign nations; cooperative threat reduction; and strategic programs, cyber, and intelligence matters.

The bill authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies regarding military construction for the Army, Navy, Air Force, defense agencies, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and Guard and Reserve Forces facilities.

The bill authorizes appropriations for base realignment and closure (BRAC) activities and prohibits an additional BRAC round.

The bill also authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies for DOE national security programs, including the National Nuclear Security Administration.

The bill includes provisions that affect the application of environmental laws such as the Endangered Species Act to the southern sea otter, the greater sage grouse, the lesser prairie chicken, and the American burying beetle.

Full Summary: 

National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016

 DIVISION A--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AUTHORIZATIONS

TITLE I--PROCUREMENT

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 101) Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for Procurement at the levels identified in section 4101 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Army Programs

(Sec. 111) Limits the availability of funds for AN/TPQ-53 radar systems until the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics submits to Congress a review of the current delegation of acquisition authority to the Program Executive Officer for Missiles and Space.

(Sec. 112) Requires the National Guard to issue guidance that prioritizes UH-60 helicopter upgrades within the Army National Guard to units with the aircraft that have the highest flight hours and utilization rates.

(Sec. 113) Requires the Army to submit to Congress a report containing options for accelerating the replacement of all UH-60A helicopters of the Army National Guard.

(Sec. 114) Expresses the sense of Congress on tactical wheeled vehicle protection kits.

Subtitle C--Navy Programs

(Sec. 121) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 to authorize the Navy to enter into a multiyear contract for a Flight III destroyer, in addition to the existing authority for a Flight IIA destroyer.

(Sec. 122) Provides economic order quantity authority for the construction of two Ford class aircraft carriers and incremental funding authority for the nuclear refueling and complex overhaul of five Nimitz class aircraft carriers.

Subtitle D--Air Force Programs

(Sec. 131) Limits the availability of funds to upgrade the executive communications of C-20 and C-37 aircraft until the Air Force certifies to Congress that the upgrades do not cause the aircraft to exceed any weight limitations or reduce operational capability of the aircraft.

(Sec. 132) Prohibits the Air Force from moving more than 18 A-10 aircraft in the Active Component to backup flying status pursuant to a DOD authorization under the Carl Levin and Howard P. ''Buck'' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015.

(Sec. 133) Prohibits the retirement of certain A-10 aircraft before December 31, 2016. Requires the Air Force to commission and report to Congress on an assessment of the required capabilities or mission platform to replace the A-10 aircraft.

(Sec. 134) Prohibits the retirement of any EC-130H aircraft. Requires the Air Force to commission and report to Congress on an assessment of the required capabilities or mission platform to replace the EC-130H aircraft.

(Sec. 135) Prohibits the Air Force from divesting or transferring any KC-10 aircraft.

(Sec. 136) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the basing process for the F-35A aircraft.

Subtitle E--Defense-Wide, Joint, and Multiservice Matters

(Sec. 141) Limits the availability of funds for joint battle command-platform equipment until after the Army submits to Congress a report providing a test and evaluation plan to address the effectiveness, suitability, and survivability shortfalls identified by the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation in the FY2014 report.

(Sec. 142) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a strategy for replacing A/MH-6 Mission Enhanced Little Bird aircraft to meet the rotary-wing, light attack, reconnaissance requirements particular to special operations.

(Sec. 143) Requires DOD to enter into an agreement with a federally funded research and development center for an assessment of the anticipated future demands of the combat logistics force ships of the Navy and the challenges the ships may face when conducting and supporting future naval operations in contested maritime environments.

(Sec. 144) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on the use in combat of two different types of enhanced 5.56 mm ammunition by the Army and the Marine Corps.

TITLE II--RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, TEST, AND EVALUATION

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 201) Authorizes appropriations for Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation at the levels identified in section 4201 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Program Requirements, Restrictions, and Limitations

(Sec. 211) Amends the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to extend the authorization for the Defense Research and Development Rapid Innovation Program through 2020.

(Sec. 212) Limits the availability of funds for advanced development and manufacturing activities under the medical countermeasure program within the Chemical-Biological Defense Program until DOD submits a specified report to Congress on the activities.

(Sec. 213) Limits the availability of funds for F-15 infrared search and track capability until after DOD reports to Congress on the requirements and cost estimates for the development and procurement of infrared search and track capability for F/A-18 and F-15 aircraft of the Navy and the Air Force.

(Sec. 214) Requires DOD to contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct an assessment of the F135 engine program.

Subtitle C--Other Matters

(Sec. 221) Modifies the authority for education partnerships to permit institutions that support technology transition or transfer activities, such as business or law schools with technology management programs, to participate.

(Sec. 222) Requires the Secretaries of the military departments and the Secretary of Defense to each develop and submit to Congress a strategy for engagement with historically black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions in the development of scientific, technical, engineering, and mathematics capabilities.

(Sec. 223) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a plan for integrating advanced weapons technologies into exercises carried out by the military to improve the development and experimentation of various concepts for employment by the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 224) Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report on the autonomic logistics information system for the F-35 Lightening II aircraft program.

(Sec. 225) Requires DOD to brief Congress on the U.S. Special Operations Command Shallow Water Combat Submersible program.

(Sec. 226) Requires DOD to report to Congress on the participation of individuals from racial or ethnic minority groups, women, and disabled individuals in graduate fellowship programs for science, mathematics, and engineering.

(Sec. 227) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD should explore using existing authorities for promoting science, technology, engineering, and mathematics programs to allow Federally Funded Research and Development Centers to help facilitate and shape a scientific and technical future workforce that can support DOD needs.

(Sec. 228) Increases the authorization of appropriations for the MV-22A digital interoperability program and specifies an offset.

(Sec. 229) Requires the Army to submit to Congress a report including the findings of a market survey and flight assessment of commercial-off-the-shelf wide-area surveillance sensors suitable for insertion into Army tactical unmanned aerial systems.

(Sec. 230) Requires the Navy and the Air Force to submit to Congress a report on the baseline and alternatives for the Navy's Tactical Air Combat Training System (TCTS) Increment II.

(Sec. 231) Revises requirements for the Secretary of Defense to promote, monitor, and evaluate programs for the communication and exchange of research, development, and technological data.

TITLE III--OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 301) Authorizes appropriations for Operation and Maintenance activities at the levels identified in section 4301 of this bill.

(Sec. 302) Authorizes appropriations for the Office of Economic Adjustment for transportation infrastructure improvements associated with congestion mitigation in urban areas related to recommendations of the 2005 Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission. Specifies an offset.

Subtitle B--Energy and Environment

(Sec. 311) Prohibits DOD from making a bulk purchase of a drop-in fuel (biofuels that are similar to conventional fuels and may be used with existing vehicles and transportation infrastructure) for operational purposes unless the fully burdened cost of the fuel is cost-competitive with a traditional fuel, subject to a national security waiver.

(Sec. 312) Establishes Southern Sea Otter Military Readiness Areas at specified offshore islands in the Southern California Bight. Exempts military readiness activities of the Navy from specified environmental laws pertaining to the southern sea otter in the Areas. Requires the Navy to monitor and report to Congress on the effects of military readiness activities on the southern otter population in the Areas.

(Sec. 313) Revises the scope of required DOD reviews of projects related to potential obstructions to aviation to: (1) cover requests for reviews by Indian tribes and landowners, (2) provide that information received from private entities is not publicly releasable, (3) eliminate categories of adverse risk, and (4) limit the applicability of the section to only energy projects.

(Sec. 314) Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to exclude from the definition of "chemical substance" any component of any article subject to the excise tax on firearms and ammunition, including shot, bullets and other projectiles, propellants when manufactured for or used in the article, and primers.

(Sec. 315) Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to exempt DOD from provisions that restrict the procurement of certain alternative or synthetic fuels unless the lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions associated with the fuel is less than or equal to emissions from the equivalent conventional fuel produced from conventional petroleum sources.

(Sec. 316) Requires DOD to obtain congressional authorization before entering into a contract for the planning, design, refurbishing, or construction of a biofuels refinery.

(Sec. 317) Requires DOD to study the impact on military readiness of any final rule that succeeds the proposed Environmental Protection Agency regulation entitled National Ambient Air Quality Standards for Ozone.

(Sec. 318) Requires DOD to report to Congress on the merger of the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Operational Energy Plans and the Office of the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Installations and Environment.

Subtitle C--Logistics and Sustainment

(Sec. 321) Requires DOD to assign performance of new requirements to members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees, or contractors based on which sector of the DOD workforce can perform the new requirement in the most cost-efficient manner.

(Sec. 322) Requires DOD to include in the periodic assessment of defense capability a determination of the extent to which the requirements associated with defense acquisition programs can be satisfied by the present and projected performance capacities of industries supporting the sectors or capabilities in the assessment.

(Sec. 323) Requires the senior acquisition executive of the Air Force instead of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics to determine if the Air Force has obtained sufficient data to establish that it is paying a fair and reasonable price for F117 engine sustainment, maintenance, repair, or overhaul.

(Sec. 324) Requires each of the service acquisition executives of the military departments to: (1) initiate a pilot program in FY2016 for product improvement under the authority provided in the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008, and (2) spend at least $5 million in working capital funds in FY2016 to support the initiative.

(Sec. 325) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on equipment purchased from foreign entities that could be manufactured in U.S. arsenals or depots.

Subtitle D--Other Matters

(Sec. 333) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a plan for the improved management and oversight of the systems, processes, and controls involved in the disposal of excess DOD property by the Defense Logistics Agency Disposition Services.

(Sec. 334) Encourages DOD to enter into contracts with third-party vendors to provide free access to wireless high-speed Internet and network connections for certain members of the Armed Forces deployed overseas.

(Sec. 335) Permits certain contracts or subcontracts entered into under the Armament Retooling and Manufacturing Support (ARMS) Initiative to include an option to extend the term for an additional 25 years.

(Sec. 336) Prohibits any DOD function performed by civilian employees that is tied to a certain base from being converted to contractor performance until DOD assesses whether sufficient outreach has been carried out to assist small businesses in the area of the base that are owned and controlled by women and socially and economically disadvantaged individuals.

TITLE IV--MILITARY PERSONNEL AUTHORIZATIONS

Subtitle A--Active Forces

(Sec. 401) Authorizes specified end strengths for Active Duty personnel of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 402) Establishes new minimum Active Duty end strengths for the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force.

Subtitle B--Reserve Forces

(Sec. 411) Authorizes specified end strengths for Selected Reserve personnel.

(Sec. 412) Authorizes specified end strengths for Reserves on Active Duty in support of the Reserves.

(Sec. 413) Authorizes specified end strengths for military technicians (dual status).

(Sec. 414) Establishes the maximum end strengths for the Reserve Components of the Army and Air Force for non-dual status technicians.

(Sec. 415) Authorizes the maximum number of Reserve Component personnel who may be on Active Duty or full-time National Guard duty during FY2016 to provide operational support.

Subtitle C--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 421) Authorizes appropriations for Military Personnel at the levels identified in section 4401 of this bill.

(Sec. 422) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report containing specified assessments, evaluations, and details regarding the force structure of the Army.

TITLE V--MILITARY PERSONNEL POLICY

Subtitle A--Officer Personnel Policy

(Sec. 501) Specifies that if the Secretary of a military department determines that one or more officers were not placed on an all-fully-qualified-list for promotion because of administrative error, the Secretary may prepare a supplemental list for promotion containing the names of the officers.

(Sec. 502) Permits the Secretaries of the military departments to defer, until age 68, the mandatory retirement age of a general or flag officer serving as Chief or Deputy Chief of Chaplains of the Army, Navy, or Air Force.

(Sec. 503) Implements GAO recommendations on the definition and availability of general and flag officer costs and requires DOD to submit a report to Congress describing the costs.

Subtitle B--Reserve Component Management

(Sec. 511) Provides that the purpose of a Reserve Component special selection board is limited to the correction of errors at a mandatory promotion board.

(Sec. 512) Includes members who occupy key federal positions in the individuals who must be screened for continued service in the Ready Reserve.

(Sec. 513) Exempts military technicians (dual-status) from civilian employee furloughs.

(Sec. 514) Requires the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to submit to Congress and other specified officials an annual report on the personnel, training, and equipment requirements for the non-federalized National Guard to support civilian authorities in preventing and responding to non-catastrophic domestic disasters.

(Sec. 515) Authorizes the use of the National Guard to support firefighting operations, missions, or activities, including aerial firefighting employment of the Modular Airborne Firefighting System, undertaken in support of a civilian authority or a state or federal agency.

(Sec. 516) Requires DOD to establish an electronic system for members of the Ready Reserve of the Armed Forces to track their operational active-duty service performed.

Subtitle C--Consolidation of Authorities to Order Members of Reserve Components to Perform Duty

 (Sec. 521) Consolidates the number of Reserve Component status category authorities under which Reserve Component members may be called to duty from 30 to 6 and directs the Secretaries concerned to develop policies and procedures to carry out the changes.

(Sec. 522) Amends Reserve duty authorities to redesignate inactive duty to encompass operational and other duties performed while in an active duty status.

(Sec. 523) Provides authorizations and limitations for the mobilization and the call-up to Active Duty or Inactive duty of the Ready Reserve, Selected Reserve, and certain members of the Individual Ready Reserve. Specifies purposes and limitations of the duty. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to organize and administer the Reserve Components and specifies authorities and limitations.

(Sec. 524) Authorizes the required training, field exercises, and other duty performed by the National Guard. Sets forth the purposes, restrictions, and limitations for a call to order of the National Guard.

(Sec. 525) Authorizes clerical and conforming amendments to the titles of the U.S. Code related to amendments made by this subtitle.

(Sec. 526) Establishes October 1, 2017, as the implementation date for this subtitle and requires the Secretaries concerned to submit an implementation plan to Congress.

Subtitle D--General Service Authorities

(Sec. 531) Provides authority through 2020 for the Secretary of a military department to develop and provide incentives to encourage individuals to accept an appointment as a commissioned officer, accept an appointment as a warrant officer, or enlist in the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 532) Amends the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act of Fiscal Year 2009 to expand the authority to conduct pilot programs on career flexibility to enhance retention of members of the Armed Forces. Removes limitations on the number of participants in the program. (Under the program, officers and enlisted members of the Armed Forces may be inactivated from active duty in order to meet personal or professional needs and returned to active duty at the end of the period of inactivation.)

(Sec. 533) Modifies the waiting period and congressional notification requirements for changes in the ground combat exclusion policy for female members of the Armed Forces. Requires DOD to notify Congress at least 30 days before a change is implemented.

(Sec. 534) Requires gender-neutral occupational standards developed by the Secretaries of the military departments to measure the combat readiness of combat units, including special operations forces.

(Sec. 535) Specifies the burden of proof for investigations conducted by an Inspector General, reviews performed by a board of correction of military records, and reviews conducted by the Secretary of Defense related to protected communications of members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 536) Permits veterans to change their name on a certificate of discharge or an order of acceptance of resignation in order to reflect a change in gender identity and a different name.

(Sec. 537) Requires the Army to develop a breastfeeding policy for female members of the Army.

(Sec. 538) Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should (1) continue to recognize and promote diversity in the Armed Forces; and (2) honor those from diverse backgrounds and religious traditions who have made sacrifices in serving the United States through the Armed Services.

(Sec. 539) Requires DOD to establish a process by which the commander of a military installation in the United States may authorize a member of the Armed Forces assigned to duty at the installation to carry a concealed personal firearm on the installation if it is necessary as a personal- or force-protection measure.

Subtitle E--Military Justice, Including Sexual Assault and Domestic Violence Prevention and Response

(Sec. 541) Requires DOD to develop a policy to standardize the training for Special Victims' Counsel, establish performance measures and standards, require a Special Victims' Counsel to have adequate criminal justice experience, and ensure that Special Victims' Counsel are assigned to locations that maximize face-to-face interactions with clients.

(Sec. 542) Authorizes DOD to provide Special Victims' Counsel services to a civilian DOD employee who is the victim of an alleged sex-related offense.

(Sec. 543) Includes former dependents of a service member or former service members among those eligible for access to a Special Victims' Counsel.

(Sec. 544) Permits victims of alleged sex-related offenses to receive representation and assistance from a Special Victims' Counsel in any retaliatory proceedings related to the victim's report of the offense.

(Sec. 545) Requires a victim of a sex-related offense to be notified of the availability of a Special Victims' Counsel prior to interviewing or requesting a statement from the victim.

(Sec. 546) Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to permit victims to participate in punitive proceedings by submitting written material for consideration by a commanding officer prior to imposing punishment, mitigating punishment, or considering an appeal under non-judicial punishment proceedings. Permits the victim to submit written material for consideration during a separation proceeding and requires the separation authority to consider the impact on the victim prior to making a decision.

(Sec. 547) Requires the report of the results of a preliminary hearing under Article 32 of the UCMJ to be provided to the victim at the same time the report is delivered to the accused.

(Sec. 548) Modifies the mandatory minimum sentence for certain sex-related offenses to require confinement for at least two years.

(Sec. 549) Requires DOD to establish a strategy to prevent retaliation against members of the Armed Forces who report or intervene on behalf of sexual assault victims.

(Sec. 550) Requires DOD to develop a plan to improve prevention and response to sexual assaults of male members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 551) Requires the Secretary of a military department to ensure that commanders of Junior and Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps units and other individuals of the Reserve Officers' Training Corps receive: (1) regular sexual assault prevention and response training, and (2) information regarding legal assistance and the sexual assault prevention and response program.

(Sec. 552) Modifies Rule 1103 of the Manual for Courts-Martial (preparation of record of trial) to require a complete record of trial in any general or special court-martial proceeding.

(Sec. 553) Requires DOD to include additional data in its annual sexual assault prevention and response report, including reports of cases under the Family Advocacy Program, data related to sexual harassment, and additional retaliation data.

(Sec. 554) Requires DOD to retain all elements of the case file in investigations of sex-related offenses for at least 50 years.

(Sec. 555) Prohibits DOD treatment facilities from releasing mental health records of alleged victims of sex-related offenses without an order from a military judge or Article 32 officer.

(Sec. 556) Requires DOD to make records of court-martial proceedings available through a public website.

(Sec. 557) Requires DOD to create a database to track sex offenders.

(Sec. 558) Requires DOD to examine the process for implementing changes to the UCMJ to develop options for streamlining the process and ensure that legal guidance is published when the changes are implemented.

Subtitle F--Member Education, Training, and Transition

(Sec. 561) Excludes any day on which a member: (1) performed full-time training or annual training duty, and (2) attended a school designated as a service school from the calculation of continuous days of Active Duty for the purpose of receiving preseparation counseling.

(Sec. 562) Requires DOD and the Department of Homeland Security to permit a member of the Armed Forces eligible for the Transition Assistance Program to receive additional training in preparation for higher education or training, career or technical training, or entrepreneurship.

(Sec. 563) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to revise the Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program to:

 expand eligibility for the program; add quality of life services to the services that DOD may enter into partnerships to provide under the program; provide flexibility in the number and timing of information, events, and activities under the program; and require the Office for Reintegration Programs to assist in the collection and analysis of best practices regarding suicide prevention. (Sec. 564) Adds one additional nomination for appointment to each military service academy by each Delegate in Congress from the territories of Guam, American Samoa, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.

(Sec. 565) Exempts two additional involuntary mobilization duty authorities from the five-year limit on reemployment rights: (1) orders of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force Reserve to active duty to respond to a major disaster or emergency; and (2) orders of the Selected Reserve to active duty for preplanned missions in support of the combatant commands.

(Sec. 566) Establishes a Job Training and Post-Service Placement Executive Committee within the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee to: (1) review policies, procedures, and practices with respect to job training and post-service placement programs; and (2) identify changes to improve job training and post-service placement.

(Sec. 567) Authorizes DOD to carry out a pilot program to enhance efforts to provide job placement assistance and related employment services directly to members of the National Guard and Reserves.

(Sec. 568) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to add six military occupational specialties to the pilot program to assess permitting enlisted members of the Armed Forces to obtain civilian credentialing or licensing for skills required for military occupational specialties or qualification for duty specialty codes.

(Sec. 569) Modifies the program to assist members serving in the Armed Forces in obtaining professional credentials to add specific requirements for providing training to members of the Armed Forces with mariner duties.

(Sec. 570) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report describing both civilian and military educational requirements necessary to meet any threats anticipated in the future security environment as described in the quadrennial defense review.

(Sec. 570a) Permits DOD and the Department of Homeland Security, with respect to the Coast Guard, to pay for a member of the active Air Force, Army, Navy, Coast Guard, the reserve components, defense contractors, or civilians with access to information systems and identified as critical to network defense to obtain professional and industry recognized credentials related to information technology and cyber security functions.

Subtitle G--Defense Dependents' Education and Military Family Readiness Matters

(Sec. 571) Authorizes appropriations for the continuation of assistance to local educational agencies impacted by the enrollment of dependent children of military members and DOD civilian employees.

(Sec. 572) Extends the authority for family support programs for immediate family members of members of the Armed Forces assigned to Special Operations Forces.

(Sec. 573) Authorizes DOD to provide grants to nonprofit organizations that provide services to improve the academic achievement of military dependent students.

(Sec. 574) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a study on the feasibility of using the Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System to track dependents of members of the Armed Forces and DOD civilian employees who are elementary or secondary education students.

(Sec. 575) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD should continue to support dependents of members of the Armed Forces in attending specialized camps for children grieving the loss of relatives or who have relatives suffering from post-traumatic stress or a behavioral health disorder.

Subtitle H--Decorations and Awards

(Sec. 581) Waives the statutory time limitation to authorize the Army to award the Distinguished-Service Cross to Edward G. Halcomb for service in the Korean War.

(Sec. 582) Prohibits Secretaries of military departments from revoking a service member's award unless the conduct of the service member during the time of the distinguished act was not honorable.

(Sec. 583) Awards the Purple Heart to six Active Duty service members who were killed during the 1995 bombing of the Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma.

(Sec. 584) Requires DOD to design and produce an Atomic Veterans Service Medal to honor retired and former members of the Armed Forces who are radiation-exposed veterans.

(Sec. 585) Deems Milton Holland who was awarded the Medal of Honor in recognition of his action in 1864 during the Battle of Chapin's Farm, Virginia, to have held the grade of captain in the regular Army.

(Sec. 586) Expresses the sense of Congress supporting the decision of the Army to posthumously promote Master Sergeant (retired) Naomi Horwitz to Sergeant Major.

Subtitle I--Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 591) Permits the U.S. Air Force Institute of Technology to charge and retain tuition for instruction of persons other than Air Force personnel detailed for instruction at the Institute.

(Sec. 592) Recognizes the service of certain members of the Reserve Components by honoring them with status as veterans.

(Sec. 593) Expresses the sense of Congress to reaffirm support for the sacrifices made by military divers.

(Sec.594) Revises the priority order of recipients of adopted military animals and requires the Secretary of the military department concerned to make animals available for adoption under certain circumstances.

(Sec. 595) Requires DOD to develop a policy to coordinate the efforts of DOD and non-governmental suicide prevention organizations.

(Sec. 596) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD and the Coast Guard should issue a Gold Star Installation Access Card to Gold Star family members who are the survivors of deceased members of the Armed Forces in order to expedite their ability to gain unescorted access to military installations to obtain services and benefits.

(Sec. 597) Requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to include specified details regarding the performance of regional offices in the annual report to Congress on quality assurance activities of the Veterans Benefits Administration.

(Sec. 598) Requires the Secretary concerned to: (1) provide preliminary mental health screenings before an individual enlists or is commissioned as an officer in an armed force, (2) use the screening as a baseline for subsequent mental health examinations, and (3) apply specified privacy laws to the screenings.

Prohibits the Secretary from using the screening to determine promotions and sets forth reporting requirements for mental and physical examinations.

(Sec. 599) Requires DOD to report to Congress on new Military Lending Act regulations related to the identification of covered borrowers, including: (1) the ability of the Defense Manpower Data Center to provide the information needed to determine whether a borrower is covered, or (2) an alternate mechanism for identifying covered borrowers.

Specifies requirements for Defense Manpower Data Center reports and meetings with private sector users.

TITLE VI--COMPENSATION AND OTHER PERSONNEL BENEFITS

Subtitle A--Pay and Allowances

(Sec. 601) Extends the authority of DOD to temporarily increase the rates of basic allowance for housing in areas impacted by natural disasters or experiencing a sudden influx of personnel.

(Sec. 602) Prohibits the Secretaries concerned from altering the amount of per diem allowance or the maximum reimbursement for a locality for members of the uniformed services and civilian employees based on the duration of a temporary duty assignment or civilian travel.

Subtitle B--Bonuses and Special and Incentive Pays

(Sec. 611) Extends certain bonus and special pay authorities for Reserve Forces.

(Sec. 612) Extends certain bonus and special pay authorities for health care professionals.

(Sec. 613) Extends certain bonus and special pay authorities for nuclear officers.

 (Sec. 614) Extends the general bonus authority for enlisted members and officers, the special bonus and incentive pay authority for nuclear officers, special aviation incentive pay and bonus authorities, the special health professions incentive pay and bonus authorities, hazardous duty pay, assignment pay or special duty pay, skill incentive pay or the proficiency bonus, the contracting bonus for Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps cadets and midshipmen, and the retention bonus for members with critical military skills or assigned to high-priority units.

(Sec. 615) Extends the authority for the aviation officer retention bonus, assignment incentive pay, the reenlistment bonus for active members, the enlistment bonus for active members, the incentive pay for members of precommissioning programs pursuing foreign language proficiency, the accession bonus for new officers in critical skills, the incentive bonus for conversion to military occupational specialty to ease personnel shortage, the incentive bonus for transfer between Armed Forces, and the accession bonus for officer candidates.

(Sec. 616) Authorizes the Navy to increase the maximum nuclear officer bonus if necessary to address declining nuclear officer retention and growing retention uncertainty.

(Sec. 617) Modifies the special aviation incentive pay and bonus authorities for officers. Permits the payment of aviation incentive pay to an officer who is not engaged in operational flying duty or proficiency flying duty, but serving in positions vital to the service. Permits the Secretaries of the military departments to continue providing aviation incentive pay to flight surgeons and other medical officers while assigned to operational flying duty. Increases the statutory limits for the aviation incentive pay and retention bonus.

(Sec. 618) Repeals the special travel and transportation allowance for survivors of deceased members of the Armed Forces from the Vietnam conflict to provide equal travel benefits regardless of the location of death or connection to a specific conflict.

Subtitle C--Modernization of Military Retirement System

(Sec. 631) Changes the current military retirement system by blending the current defined benefit retirement plan with a defined contribution plan allowing service members to contribute to a Thrift Savings Plan account with a government contribution matching program.

(Sec. 632) Changes the current uniformed services retirement system by blending the current defined benefit retirement plan with a defined contribution plan, lump sum career continuation pay, and retention bonuses paid at defined career milestones, while continuing a 20-year defined annuity.

(Sec. 633) Changes the current military retirement system by adding a mandatory lump sum career continuation pay at 12 years of service with an agreement by the service member to continue in service for 4 more years.

(Sec. 634) Establishes October 1, 2017, as the effective date for this subtitle, and requires the Secretaries concerned to submit an implementation plan to Congress.

Subtitle D--Commissary and Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentality Benefits and Operations

(Sec. 641) Requires DOD to ensure that there are no changes to the second destination transportation policy that currently applies to fresh fruit and vegetable supplies for commissaries in Asia and the Pacific until the Defense Commissary Agency submits a study to Congress.

(Sec. 642) Prohibits DOD from taking any actions to replace or consolidate the defense commissary and exchange systems prior to the submission of a required report on the defense commissary system.

Subtitle E--Other Matters

(Sec. 651) Requires DOD to increase the frequency of and make specified improvements to financial literacy and preparedness training for members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 652) Requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to make available for purchase a memorial headstone or marker for members of a National Guard or Reserve component who performed training but did not serve on active duty.

 TITLE VII--HEALTH CARE PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--TRICARE and Other Health Care Benefits

(Sec. 701) Requires DOD and the VA to establish a joint uniform formulary with respect to pharmaceutical agents that are critical for the transition of an individual from receiving treatment furnished by DOD to treatment furnished by the VA.

 (Sec. 702) Requires DOD to ensure that every military medical treatment facility has a sufficient stock of Food and Drug Administration approved methods of contraception.

(Sec. 703) Requires DOD to provide a sufficient supply of prescription contraception to a female member of the Armed Forces prior to deployment.

(Sec. 704) Requires DOD to provide uninterrupted access to infertility treatment for members of the Armed Forces and their dependents.

(Sec. 705) Modifies residency requirements for certain beneficiaries to receive access to TRICARE Prime. Increases the authorization of appropriations for the Defense Health Program and specifies an offset.

Subtitle B--Health Care Administration

(Sec. 711) Requires DOD to establish a unified medical command to provide medical services to the Armed Forces and other DOD health care beneficiaries.

(Sec. 712) Establishes criteria under which licensed mental health counselors may be reimbursed under the TRICARE program.

(Sec. 713) Prohibits DOD from realigning or restructuring a military medical treatment facility until after a report is submitted to Congress.

(Sec. 714) Authorizes DOD to conduct a pilot program to evaluate whether operating a network of preferred retail pharmacies will generate cost savings.

Subtitle C--Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 721) Extends the authority for the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund for five years.

(Sec. 722) Extends the authority for the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund through FY2017.

(Sec. 723) Limits the funds authorized by this bill that may be used for DOD Healthcare Management Systems Modernization until DOD makes a specified certification required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014.

(Sec. 724) Requires the peer-reviewed Psychological Health and Traumatic Brain Injury Research Program to conduct a study on blast injury mechanics.

(Sec. 725) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding mental health counseling for members of the Armed Forces and their families.

(Sec. 726) Makes permanent the authority to provide transportation for certain dependents receiving obstetrical anesthesia services related to childbirth.

 TITLE VIII--ACQUISITION POLICY, ACQUISITION MANAGEMENT, AND RELATED MATTERS

(Sec. 800) Expresses the sense of Congress that an improved defense acquisition system should be successful (timely delivery of affordable and effective military equipment and services), proactive, agile, transparent, and innovative.

Subtitle A--Acquisition Policy and Management

(Sec. 801) Requires the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps to each submit to Congress a report on efforts to link and streamline the requirements, acquisition, and budget processes within the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps.

(Sec. 802) Requires the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Chief of Naval Operations, the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and the Commandant of the Marine Corps to review their current individual authorities related to defense acquisitions to develop recommendations to further or advance their roles in the development of requirements, acquisition processes, and the associated DOD budget practices.

(Sec. 803) Requires DOD to contract with an independent research entity that is a not-for-profit entity or a federally funded research and development center to study the factors leading to the filing of bid protests.

(Sec. 804) Requires DOD to establish and maintain a centralized capability to oversee the making of commercial item determinations for DOD procurements and to provide public access to the determinations. Sets forth procedures and requirements for procuring commercial items when a prior determination has been made for the same item.

(Sec. 805) Eliminates a requirement that the contracting officer, prior to making a determination that an item is a commercial item, determine in writing that the offeror of the item has submitted sufficient information to evaluate the reasonableness of the price through price analysis.

(Sec. 806) Permits the head of an agency to enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property if there is a reasonable expectation that the use of a multiyear contract would result in lower total anticipated costs of carrying out the program than if the program were carried out through annual contracts. (Under current law, the head of an agency must determine that savings will be achieved prior to entering into the contract.)

(Sec. 807) Limits the expenditure of funds authorized for the operation of the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness until specified conditions are met regarding DOD's compliance with the requirement for an inventory of contracts for services.

Subtitle B--Workforce Development and Related Matters

(Sec. 811) Makes permanent the authority for the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund and the associated expedited hiring authority.

(Sec. 812) Reinstitutes a dual-track career path for officers and enlisted personnel to gain experience and receive credit for both a primary career in combat arms and a functional secondary career in the acquisition field.

(Sec. 813) Includes acquisition matters addressed by military personnel in the definition of "joint matters" to enable military acquisition professionals to receive joint professional credit and end certain double experience requirements for officers who serve in acquisition positions.

(Sec. 814) Requires DOD to add an acquisition skills assessment to the biennial strategic workforce plan on critical skills and competencies of the civilian employee workforce.

(Sec. 815) Requires DOD to provide mandatory training for members of the Armed Forces and DOD employees responsible for conducting market research.

(Sec. 816) Requires DOD to contract with an independent research entity to study DOD strategic planning related to the defense acquisition workforce.

(Sec. 817) Extends the demonstration project relating to certain acquisition personnel management policies and procedures.

Subtitle C--Weapon Systems Acquisition and Related Matters

(Sec. 821) Expresses the sense of the Congress that DOD, Congress, and industry should develop an acquisition system characterized by highly disciplined program initiation coupled with agile program execution and balanced oversight.

(Sec. 822) Requires an acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program and each major system approved by a Milestone Decision Authority. Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics to issue and maintain requirements for the content and the review and approval process for the strategies.

(Sec. 823) Requires the program acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program or major system to include an identification of major program risks and a risk management and mitigation strategy.

(Sec. 824) Modifies requirements for the determination of contract types for major defense acquisition programs and major systems.

(Sec. 825) Requires the Milestone Decision Authority to: (1) make a written determination, in lieu of a certification, before approving milestone A (initiates technology maturation and risk reduction) for major defense acquisition programs, and (2) provide an explanation of the basis for the determination to Congress upon request.

(Sec. 826) Requires the Milestone Decision Authority to: (1) make a written determination, in lieu of a certification, before approving milestone B (initiates engineering and manufacturing development) for major defense acquisition programs, and (2) provide an explanation of the basis for the determination to Congress upon request.

Subtitle D--Industrial Base Matters

(Sec. 831) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for FY1991 to codify and amend the Mentor-Protege Program, which provides incentives for major DOD contractors to furnish disadvantaged small business concerns with assistance to enhance capabilities to perform under DOD contracts.

(Sec. 832) Amends the Small Business Act to require the Small Business Administration (SBA) to annually provide to Congress certification of the accuracy and completeness of data reported on bundled and consolidated contracts. Requires GAO to report on the effectiveness of the certification process and assess whether contracts were accurately labeled as bundled or consolidated.

(Sec. 833) Requires: (1) the senior procurement executive or chief acquisition officer to announce through a public website that a determination has been made to bundle or consolidate contracts, and (2) the head of a contracting agency to announce through a public website that a determination has been made regarding a substantial bundling of contracts for a proposed procurement plan. Specifies requirements for the timing of the announcements.

(Sec. 834) Provides that Small Business Act requirements for certain contracts apply to contracts for goods, but not services or construction.

(Sec. 835) Requires DOD to contract with an independent entity to review: (1) regulations, practices, and sustainment requirements related to government access to and use of intellectual property rights of private sector firms; and (2) practices related to the procurement, management, and use of intellectual property rights to facilitate competition in sustainment of weapon systems throughout their life-cycle.

(Sec. 836) Requires certain auxiliary ship components to be procured from a manufacturer in the national technology and industrial base (the persons and organizations engaged in research, development, production, integration, services, or information technology activities conducted within the United States and Canada).

(Sec. 837) Requires DOD to ensure that every DOD tactical missile program that uses solid propellant as the primary propulsion system has at least one rocket motor supplier within the national technology and industrial base.

(Sec. 838) Adds the Administrator of the SBA to the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council.

(Sec. 839) Increases the amount of SBA surety bond guarantees from 70% to 90% percent. Requires the GAO to study the surety bond program and the impact of this amendment on the program. (A surety bond is a three-party instrument between a surety who agrees to be responsible for the debt or obligation of another, a contractor, and a project owner.)

(Sec. 840) Establishes certification requirements for Commercial Market Representatives and modifies the certification requirements for Procurement Center Representatives and Business Opportunity Specialists.

(Sec. 841) Includes consideration of success in attainment of small business subcontracting goals as a part of agency responsibilities for achieving small business goals.

(Sec. 842) Amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to revise requirements for small businesses located in base closure areas to participate in the Historically Underutilized Business Zone (HUBZone) program.

(Sec. 843) Requires agencies to consider the capabilities and past performances of the small businesses that submit offers as teams or joint ventures for a multiple award contract or when the contract is bundled or consolidated.

(Sec. 844) Requires the SBA to:

 ensure the participation of a wide variety of industries and a broad spectrum of small businesses within each industry to meet small business contracting goals, and develop a scorecard program for evaluating federal agency compliance with small business contracting goals. Specifies requirements for the scorecard and requires GAO to review the methodology. Requires the SBA to report to Congress on specified details regarding contracts awarded to small businesses.

(Sec. 845) Establishes an Office of Hearings and Appeals in the SBA to: (1) impartially decide matters relating to certain program decisions of the Administrator, and (2) handle Freedom of Information Act requests and maintain records pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974. Establishes procedures for the Office of Hearing and Appeals to consider petitions for the reconsideration of size standards for small business concerns.

(Sec. 846) Establishes limitations on the use of reverse auctions for awarding certain government contracts.

(Sec. 847) Expresses the sense of Congress that procurement authority for specialized fire hoses for the U.S. Forest Service should be reestablished as an activity of the General Services Administration.

Subtitle E--Other Matters

(Sec. 851) Requires the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation to consider the potential for increases in program cost estimates or delays in schedule estimates in the implementation of policies, procedures, and activities related to operational test and evaluation, and to take action to ensure that the activities do not unnecessarily impede schedules or increase costs.

(Sec. 852) Requires a contracting officer to consider evidence provided by an offeror of recent purchase prices paid by the government for the same or similar commercial items in establishing price reasonableness if the previous prices remain a valid reference for comparison after considering other relevant factors.

(Sec. 853) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 to make permanent the transaction authority for the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency to carry out certain prototype projects that are directly relevant to enhancing the mission effectiveness of military personnel and the supporting platforms, systems, components, or materials proposed to be acquired or developed by DOD, or to improvement of platforms, systems, components, or materials in use by the Armed Forces.

 Requires all parties to the transaction other than the federal government to be small businesses or nontraditional defense contractors, unless exceptional circumstances exist that require innovative business arrangements that are not feasible under another contract type.

(Sec. 854) Raises acquisition thresholds, including the simplified acquisition threshold, the micro-purchase threshold, the emergency procurement threshold, and the small business reservation threshold.

(Sec. 855) Changes the rounding method used for making inflation adjustments to certain acquisition-related dollar thresholds.

(Sec. 856) Repeals the requirement for separate manpower estimates for major defense acquisition programs.

(Sec. 857) Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics to examine the decision authority related to acquisition of services and to develop and issue guidance to improve capabilities related to services contracts requirements development, source selection, and contract oversight and management.

(Sec. 858) States the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense, the Defense Business Council, and other specified officials for the management of defense business systems.

(Sec. 859) Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics to ensure that specified instructions and guidance are considered during preliminary design review of products that require strategic materials (critical to national security or specialty metals) over the life cycle of the product.

(Sec. 860) Requires DOD to use best value tradeoff source selection methods to the maximum extent practicable when procuring an item of personal protective equipment or critical safety items.

(Sec. 861) Expands the eligibility for contractors to include costs for rework and corrective action related to counterfeit electronic parts as allowable costs under DOD contracts.

(Sec. 862) Provides that the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Developmental Test and Evaluation and the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Systems Engineering advise the Milestone Decision Authority regarding review and approval of developmental test plans and systems engineering plans, instead of reviewing and approving or disapproving the plans.

(Sec. 863) Extends the temporary limitation on the aggregate annual amounts available for DOD contract services.

(Sec. 864) Requires DOD to establish values and metrics for the services being procured and review the offeror's past performance prior to using a lowest price, technically acceptable (LPTA) evaluation method for the procurement of audit or audit readiness services.

(Sec. 865) Modifies the enhanced authority for DOD to acquire products and services produced in Afghanistan, Central Asian states, and Djibouti to create an exception from the requirements for products not produced in those countries, but included on the procurement list for products or services provided by a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind or other severely disabled individuals.

(Sec. 866) Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to prescribe a regulation making clear that agency acquisition personnel are permitted and encouraged to engage in responsible and constructive exchanges with industry, if the exchanges are consistent with existing laws and regulations and do not promote an unfair competitive advantage to particular firms.

(Sec. 867) Requires the Office of Management and Budget to submit to Congress a plan for improving management of IT programs and projects.

(Sec. 868) Requires the President of the Defense Acquisition University to convene a review board annually with faculty representatives from relevant professional schools and degree-granting institutions of DOD and military departments to review and synchronize defense acquisition curricula across DOD.

(Sec. 869) Specifies that the Defense Acquisition University should provide for research and analysis of defense acquisition policy issues from academic institutions that offer in-depth analysis of the entire defense acquisition decision support system from both a business and public policy perspective and from an operational and information sciences perspective.

(Sec. 870) Requires DOD to conduct and brief Congress on an assessment of the application of the Open Trusted Technology Provider Standard to DOD procurements for information technology and cyber security acquisitions.

(Sec. 871) Modifies the justification and approval process for certain sole-source contracts for small business concerns.

TITLE IX--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE ORGANIZATION AND MANAGEMENT

(Sec. 901) Redesignates the Department of the Navy as the Department of the Navy and Marine Corps, and changes the title of its Secretary to the Secretary of the Navy and Marine Corps.

(Sec. 902) Changes the requirement for the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to review the Unified Command Plan including the missions, responsibilities, and force structure of each combatant command, from not less than every two years to not less than every four years.

(Sec. 903) Revises the functions of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to include additional joint force integration functions currently overseen by the Chairman, as a result of the disestablishment of U.S. Joint Forces Command and the deletion of that command from the Unified Command Plan.

(Sec. 904) Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding the U.S. Marine Corps.

(Sec. 905) Amends the existing requirement for DOD to develop a plan for streamlining DOD management headquarters to require an accurate baseline accounting of defense headquarters budgets and personnel, and more specific information on actual and planned reductions in management headquarters. Requires DOD to implement its planned reduction in management headquarters budgets and personnel for certain organizations in the National Capital Region. Provides that civilian employees funded from working capital funds are not subject to the reduction requirement.

(Sec. 906) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD should proceed with the collaborative work with employee representatives on the "New Beginnings" performance management and workforce incentive system and begin implementing the new system at the earliest possible date.

(Sec. 907) Establishes guidelines for the conversion of functions performed by civilian or contractor personnel to performance by military personnel.

TITLE X--GENERAL PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--Financial Matters

(Sec. 1001) Permits DOD to make transfers between amounts authorized for FY2016 in division A of this bill, subject to specified limitations and a congressional notification requirement.

(Sec. 1002) Permits DOD to transfer up to $150 million to the nuclear weapons and naval reactor programs of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) if the amount authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for FY2016 for the weapons activities of the NNSA is less than $8.9 billion.

(Sec. 1003) Requires DOD to work with the Federal Accounting Standards Advisory Board to establish accounting standards to value large and unordinary general property, plant, and equipment items.

(Sec. 1004) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report ranking all military departments and defense agencies in order of how advanced they are in achieving auditable financial statements as required by law.

Subtitle B--Counter-Drug Activities

(Sec. 1011) Extends the authority to provide support for counterdrug activities of certain foreign governments.

(Sec. 1012) States the policy of the United States to prioritize a Plan Central America to address the threatening levels of violence, instability, illicit trafficking, and transnational organized crime that challenge the sovereignty of Central American nations and security of the United States.

Subtitle C--Naval Vessels and Shipyards

(Sec. 1021) Restricts the overhaul or repair of U.S. vessels in foreign shipyards. Excludes emergency or voyage repairs required during an overseas homeporting period.

(Sec. 1022) Extends the authority of DOD to use Navy operation and maintenance accounts to fund the cost of meals on U.S. naval and naval auxiliary vessels for non-military personnel.

(Sec. 1023) Limits the use of FY2016 funds for the retirement, inactivation, or storage of Ticonderoga class cruisers and Whidbey Island-class amphibious ships. Requires the modernization of two Ticonderoga-class cruisers to begin in FY2016 after sufficient materials are available to begin the modernization period. Limits the modernization period to two years, and permits the Navy to extend the period for another six months.

(Sec. 1024) Prohibits the removal of ballistic missile capabilities from any of the Ticonderoga class cruisers until the Navy certifies to Congress that it has obtained the ballistic missile capabilities required by the most recent Navy Force Structure Assessment or determined to upgrade the cruisers with an equal or improved capability.

Subtitle D--Counterterrorism

(Sec. 1031) Makes permanent the authority to make rewards for providing information or non-lethal assistance to U.S. government personnel or allied forces participating in a combined operation conducted outside the United States against terrorism, or providing information or assistance beneficial to force protection associated with the operation.

(Sec. 1032) Removes an exemption of operations executed within the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force from congressional notification requirements for sensitive military operations.

(Sec. 1033) Modifies reporting requirements for funds related to programs for combating terrorism.

(Sec. 1034) Amends a provision of Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 requiring the President to report to Congress on individuals detained at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo), including a summary of all contact between individuals formerly detained at Guantanamo and individuals associated with a foreign terrorist group, and whether any of the contacts included information or discussion about hostilities against the United States or its allies. Requires the summary of contacts between individuals to contain any means of communication and all contact, regardless of content.

(Sec. 1035) Requires the President to include in reports to Congress details regarding recidivism of individuals formerly detained at Guantanamo.

(Sec. 1036) Prohibits the use of funds to transfer or release detainees at Guantanamo to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions.

(Sec. 1037) Prohibits DOD from using funds to modify or construct any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any detainee transferred from Guantanamo for the purposes of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under control of DOD.

(Sec. 1038) Prohibits DOD from using funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release of any individual detained at Guantanamo to a combat zone.

(Sec. 1039) Prohibits DOD from using funds to transfer or release any individual detained at Guantanamo to the individual's country of origin or any other foreign country or entity, unless DOD provides a certification to Congress addressing specified requirements.

Prohibits DOD from using funds to transfer an individual to a country if there is a confirmed case of any individual transferred from Guantanamo to the same country or entity engaging in terrorist activity after the transfer.

Permits DOD to waive certification requirements for national security, subject to reporting requirements and exceptions.

(Sec. 1040) Requires the Department of Justice and DOD to submit to Congress specified correspondence related to the transfer of individuals detained at Guantanamo to Qatar.

(Sec. 1041) Requires DOD to submit to the House Committee on Armed Services unredacted copies of all documents produced in response to the committee's June 9, 2014, request for information regarding the transfer of five individuals from Guantanamo to Qatar. Limits the obligation of FY2016 funds by Office of the Secretary of Defense until DOD submits unredacted copies of certain documents to the committee.

(Sec. 1042) Prohibits DOD from using funds for the transfer or release of any individual detained at Guantanamo to Yemen or any entity within Yemen.

Subtitle E--Miscellaneous Authorities and Limitations

(Sec. 1051) Expands the transfer authority provided to the National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund from the Department of the Navy to DOD. Provides the Navy with authority to:

 enter into economic order quantity contracts for ballistic missile submarines and other nuclear powered vessels, use the Fund to enter into contracts for advance construction of national sea-based deterrence vessels, use incremental funding to enter into contracts for certain items, and use the Fund to provide incentives for investments in critical infrastructure at nuclear capable shipyards and critical sub-tier vendors. (Sec. 1052) Requires DOD to create a website providing information on property transferred under the DOD excess property program. Establishes eligibility requirements that must be met prior to transferring certain types of property to recipients. Requires a federally funded research and development center, the GAO, and DOD to review program objectives, efficacy, and training requirements.

(Sec. 1053) Limits the transfer of certain AH-64 Apache helicopters from the Army National Guard to the regular Army or the reduction of related personnel levels before June 30, 2016.

(Sec. 1054) Requires DOD to amend the Air Transportation Eligibility Regulation to authorize space-available travel for environmental morale leave by unaccompanied spouses and dependent children of service members deployed for at least 30 consecutive days under priority category IV.

(Sec. 1055) Permits DOD to establish a pilot program to assess information-related and strategic communications capabilities to support the tactical, operational, and strategic requirements of the various combatant commanders, including urgent and emergent operational needs, and the operational and theater security cooperation plans of the Geographic and Functional Combatant Commanders.

(Sec. 1056) Prohibits the Navy from using FY2016 funds to retire, prepare to retire, transfer, or place in storage any Helicopter Sea Combat Squadron 84 (HSC-84) or Helicopter Sea Combat Squadron 85 (HSC-85) aircraft or to change the manning levels of the squadrons. Permits a waiver if the Secretary of the Navy certifies that he has conducted a cost-benefit analysis identifying savings to DOD and has identified a replacement capability to meet all operational requirements.

(Sec. 1057) Prohibits the use of funds for the destruction of anti-personnel landmines of the United States until specified conditions are met. Includes an exception for any anti-personnel land mine that has become unsafe or poses a safety risk if not demilitarized or destroyed.

(Sec. 1058) Prohibits the use of funds to modify command and control relationships to give Fleet Forces Command operational and administrative control of Navy forces assigned to the Pacific Fleet.

(Sec. 1059) Prohibits the closure of Guantanamo and requires the President to ensure that the obligations of the United States under Article III of the Treaty between the United States and Cuba signed on May 29, 1934, are met.

(Sec. 1060) Prohibits the use of funds to: (1) close or abandon Guantanamo, (2) relinquish control of Guantanamo to Cuba, or (3) modify the 1934 treaty Between the United States and Cuba, including a modification of the boundaries of Guantanamo, unless it is ratified by the Senate.

(Sec. 1060a) Permits DOD to participate in a Civilian Aviation Asset Military Partnership Pilot Program to provide grants to eligible airports to: (1) improve aviation infrastructure; or (2) to repair, replace, or otherwise improve an eligible tower facility.

(Sec. 1060b) Permits DOD to sell or donate excess personal property to federal or state agencies for border security activities.

(Sec. 1060c) Prohibits the use of funds to deactivate the 440th airlift wing until DOD certifies that the deactivation will not affect the military readiness for the airborne and special operations units stationed at Fort Bragg, North Carolina.

Subtitle F--Studies and Reports

(Sec. 1061) Requires DOD to include in the annual budget submission a report to Congress containing summaries of the defense planning guidance and contingency planning guidance. Limits the expenditure of Operation and Maintenance--Defense-Wide funds for the Office of the Secretary until after the report is submitted.

(Sec. 1062) Amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act to provide GAO with additional time to complete a required report on the NNSA budget request.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 to eliminate a requirement for GAO to conduct a final review of all projects carried out by the Department of Energy's Office of Environmental Management using American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 funds.

(Sec. 1063) Requires DOD to report to Congress on plans for implementing the geographically distributed force laydown in the area of responsibility of U.S. Pacific Command.

(Sec. 1064) Requires DOD to contract with an independent research entity to carry out a study of the DOD national security strategy formulation process.

 (Sec. 1065) Requires the Office of Net Assessment to conduct a study on DOD's role in the formulation of long-term strategy.

(Sec. 1066) Requires DOD to report to Congress on the potential threat posed to members of the Armed Forces of the U.S. Naval Forces Central Command and the U.S. Fifth Fleet from Naval Support Activity Bahrain, and their families, should there be an increase in violence in Bahrain.

(Sec. 1067) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report addressing the suitability of existing capabilities to detect, identify, and disable remotely piloted aircraft operating within special use and restricted airspace.

(Sec. 1068) Requires the Air Force to submit to Congress a report addressing the immediate and critical training and operational needs of the remotely piloted aircraft community.

(Sec. 1069) Exempts meetings of the National Commission on the Future of the Army from specified requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, unless the meetings are attended by five or more members of the Commission.

Subtitle G--Repeal or Revision of National Defense Reporting Requirements

(Sec. 1071) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to military personnel issues.

(Sec. 1072) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to readiness.

(Sec. 1073) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to Naval vessels and the Merchant Marine.

(Sec. 1074) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to nuclear weapons, proliferation, and related matters.

(Sec. 1075) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to missile defense.

(Sec. 1076) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to acquisition.

(Sec. 1077) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to civilian personnel.

(Sec. 1078) Repeals or revises specified reporting requirements related to combating terrorism, technological maturity and integration risk of critical technologies, system engineering, the Regional Defense Counterterrorism Fellowship Program, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), airlift requirements, in-kind payments, and the Navy Next Generation Enterprise Networks Program.

Subtitle H--Other Matters

(Sec. 1081) Makes technical and clerical amendments to existing laws.

 (Sec. 1082) Requires DOD to establish an executive agent for and report to Congress on the oversight and management of alternative compensatory control measures.

(Sec. 1083) Eliminates a requirement for the Navy to make funds available annually to support the Ocean Research Advisory Panel.

(Sec. 1084) Requires DOD to include with the annual budget submission specified details regarding the level of readiness of Civil Reserve Air Fleet carriers.

(Sec. 1085) Authorizes the Army to transfer surplus firearms, spare parts, and related accessories to the Corporation for the Promotion of Rifle Practice and Firearms Safety, also known as the Civilian Marksmanship Program.

(Sec. 1086) Modifies specified administrative requirements for transferring aircraft from the Reserve Components to the Active Components of the Air Force.

(Sec. 1087) Reestablishes the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack and sets forth requirements for membership, the purpose, and duties.

(Sec. 1088) Requires DOD to develop a strategy to counter unconventional warfare threats posed by adversarial state and non-state actors.

(Sec. 1089) Requires the Navy to submit a mine countermeasures master plan to Congress with the annual budget submission for each fiscal year from FY2018-FY2023.

(Sec. 1090) Requires DOD and the Department of State to notify and brief Congress after an evacuation operation of a U.S. embassy or consulate involving the use of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 1091) Requires DOD to determine and disclose the transportation costs incurred for certain congressional trips outside the United States.

(Sec. 1092) Requires the President to designate an existing federal officer as the Interagency Hostage Recovery Coordinator to coordinate efforts to secure the release of U.S. persons who are hostages of hostile groups or state sponsors of terrorism. Specifies duties, reporting requirements, and limitations on authority for the position.

(Sec. 1093) Specifies procedures, requirements, and limitations that apply when members of the Armed Forces provide support to civilian law enforcement agencies during situations involving bombings of places of public use, government facilities, public transportation systems, and infrastructure facilities.

(Sec. 1094) Expresses the sense of Congress that a technical correction to the Carl Levin and Howard P. "Buck" McKeon National Defense Authorization Act of Fiscal Year 2015 should be enacted in order to expeditiously carry out the intent of provisions authorizing the refinancing of the loan funding the Pacific Coast groundfish fishing capacity reduction program.

(Sec. 1095) Requires the President to issue an annual proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe two minutes of silence on Veterans Day.

(Sec. 1096) Requires the Air Force to conduct a business case analysis of the decision to maintain 10 C-130J aircraft at Keesler Air Force Base, Mississippi.

(Sec. 1097) Expresses the sense of Congress that the National Guard should seek ways to improve and expand its communications and networking capabilities to provide for enhanced performance and resilience in the face of cyber-attacks or disruptions, as well as other instances of degradation.

(Sec. 1098) Expresses the sense of Congress that taxpayers should not pay any organization to honor the service of members of the Armed Forces and that funds that would have been used for this purpose should be directed to post-traumatic stress disorder research and treatment.

TITLE XI--CIVILIAN PERSONNEL MATTERS

(Sec. 1101) Amends the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense, the Global War on Terror, and Hurricane Recovery, 2006 to extend the authority for federal agencies to grant allowances, benefits, and gratuities comparable to those provided to members of the foreign service to an agency's civilian employees on official duty in a combat zone.

(Sec. 1102) Authorizes DOD to provide additional allowances and benefits to employees of the Defense Clandestine Service.

(Sec. 1103) Extends the authority for overtime pay for Navy employees assigned to temporary duty to perform work aboard or dockside in direct support of the nuclear aircraft carrier that is forward deployed in Japan.

(Sec. 1104) Permits the noncompetitive conversion of students that have graduated from an applicable institution of higher education to a permanent appointment. Increases the limit on the number of appointments allowable in a calendar year.

(Sec. 1105) Provides hiring preferences for federal employment to members of a Reserve Component of the Armed Forces who have successfully completed Officer Candidate Training or entry level skill training and are performing a 6-year commitment, have completed 10 years of service, or are retired.

 TITLE XII--MATTERS RELATING TO FOREIGN NATIONS

Subtitle A--Assistance and Training

(Sec. 1201) Extends the authority for DOD to provide supplies, services, transportation, and other logistical support to coalition forces supporting U.S. operations in Iraq and Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1202) Requires DOD, in coordination with the Department of State, to develop a strategic framework for DOD security cooperation to guide prioritization of resources and activities.

(Sec. 1203) Extends and modifies the authorization for the National Guard State Partnership Program (SPP) to:

 specify that SPP should support the national interests and security cooperation goals and objectives of the United States; require the National Guard to establish, maintain, update, and submit to DOD a list of core competencies, consistent with the roles and missions of the Armed Forces to support SPP activities; and require DOD to establish a fund to administer and execute the funds provided for SPP and to include the fund in budget requests. (Sec. 1204) Extends the authorization for non-reciprocal exchanges of defense personnel between the United States and foreign countries.

(Sec. 1205) Permits specified funds to be used to monitor and evaluate DOD overseas humanitarian, disaster, and civic aid programs. Requires DOD to brief Congress on mechanisms to evaluate the programs.

Subtitle B--Matters Relating to Afghanistan and Pakistan

(Sec. 1211) Extends the Commanders' Emergency Response Program in Afghanistan and authorizes FY2016 appropriations.

(Sec. 1212) Extends the authority for reimbursement of coalition nations for support provided to the United States for military operations in Afghanistan.

Extends the requirement for DOD to: (1) notify Congress prior to making any reimbursement to Pakistan, of any logistical, military, or other support that Pakistan provides to the United States; and (2) certify, prior to providing reimbursement, that Pakistan has met specified requirements.

Provides that $400 million of the total amount of reimbursements and support authorized for Pakistan during FY2016 shall not be eligible for a national security waiver unless DOD certifies that Pakistan has met specified requirements.

(Sec. 1213) Expresses the sense of Congress on U.S. policy and strategy in Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1214) Extends the authority to acquire products and services produced in countries along a major supply route of Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1215) Extends the authority to transfer defense articles and provide defense services to the military and security forces of Afghanistan. Extends the quarterly reporting requirement for this authority. Provides that excess defense articles transferred from DOD stocks to the military and security forces of Afghanistan will not be subject to specified authorities and limitations in the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.

(Sec. 1216) Expresses the sense of Congress that it is in the interest of the United States to continue to assist Afghan partners who have served as translators or interpreters and those who have performed sensitive and trusted activities for U.S. forces.

Amends the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 to provide special immigrant status for Afghans employed in Afghanistan by the Resolute Support Mission (a NATO-led mission to provide further training, advice and assistance for the Afghan security forces and institutions) or any successor organization.

(Sec. 1217) Requires the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State to report to Congress on efforts of the Secretaries to engage U.S. manufacturers in procurement opportunities related to equipping the Afghan National Security Forces.

(Sec. 1218) Requires the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction to report to Congress on the extent to which the Office of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction has adequate access to financial records of the government of Afghanistan to audit the use of funds authorized for assistance for Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1219) Expresses the sense of Congress that Dr. Shakil Afridi is an international hero and that Pakistan should release him immediately from prison.

Subtitle C--Matters Relating to Syria and Iraq

(Sec. 1221) Extends the authority for the Office of Security Cooperation in Iraq to conduct training activities in support of the Iraqi Ministry of Defense and Counter Terrorism Service personnel. Limits FY2016 funding authorized for this purpose and sets forth reporting requirements.

(Sec. 1222) Requires DOD and the Department of State to submit to Congress a comprehensive strategy for the Middle East and to counter Islamic extremism.

(Sec. 1223) Authorizes appropriations for assistance to the military and security forces of Iraq and requires specified funds to be used for direct assistance to the Kurdish Peshmerga, the Sunni tribal security forces with a national security mission, and the Iraqi Sunni National Guard.

Requires DOD and the Department of State to: (1) submit to Congress an assessment of the extent to which Iraq is meeting certain conditions relating to political inclusion of ethnic and sectarian minorities within the security forces of Iraq, and (2) withhold FY2016 assistance to Iraq if the conditions are not met.

Requires that the Kurdish Peshmerga, the Sunni tribal security forces with a national security mission, and the Iraqi Sunni National Guard be deemed a country, and receive specified assistance under this section, if Iraq has not met the conditions or an assessment is not submitted.

(Sec. 1224) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on U.S. Armed Forces deployed in support of Operation Inherent Resolve (operations in Iraq and Syria against the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant or ISIL).

(Sec. 1225) Modifies the authority to provide assistance to the vetted Syrian opposition to permit DOD to submit a reprogramming or transfer request to use funds made available for the Syria Train and Equip Fund for this purpose. Sets forth reporting requirements, including the submission of a comprehensive strategy regarding Iraq and Syria, and updates and certifications regarding the strategy.

(Sec. 1226) Authorizes DOD to provide assistance on a reimbursement basis to the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan to support and enhance the efforts of its Armed Forces to sustain security along its border with the Syrian Arab Republic and the Republic of Iraq. Authorizes appropriations and sets forth reporting requirements for this authority.

(Sec. 1227) Requires DOD to report to Congress on the efforts of Turkey to fight terrorism, including efforts to combat the flow of foreign fighters through its country into Syria, and its relationship with Hamas.

(Sec. 1228) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report that assesses the potential effectiveness, risks, and operational requirements of the establishment of: (1) a no-fly zone over part or all of Syria, and (2) one or more safe zones in Syria for internally displaced people or for the facilitation of humanitarian assistance.

Subtitle D--Matters Relating to Iran

(Sec. 1231) Extends the requirement for an annual report on the military power of Iran and adds a requirement to include an assessment of transfers of military equipment, technology, and training to Iran from non-Iranian sources.

(Sec. 1232) Expresses the sense of the Congress on Iran's nuclear program and military activities.

(Sec. 1233) Requires DOD to report to Congress on the military posture required in the Middle East to deter Iran from developing a nuclear weapon.

(Sec. 1234) Prohibits DOD from authorizing certain military-to-military exchanges and contact with Iran until DOD certifies that Iran: (1) has ended its ballistic missile program, (2) is no longer listed by the Secretary of State as a state sponsor of terrorism; and (3) has recognized Israel as a Jewish state. Includes an exception for search-and-rescue or humanitarian operations or exercises.

(Sec. 1235) Requires DOD to provide Congress with a copy of any security agreement or commitment associated with Iran's nuclear weapons program that has been provided by the United States to any country in the Middle East. Prohibits the use of FY2016 funds for the security agreement or commitment until DOD certifies that the agreement has been provided to Congress.

Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to provide DOD with an analysis of the U.S. military force structure and posture, as well as the associated costs, required to meet any security agreement or commitment in the Middle East.

(Sec. 1236) Provides that nothing in this bill authorizes the use of force against Iran.

Subtitle E--Matters Relating to the Russian Federation

(Sec. 1241) Requires DOD to provide specified updates and notifications to Congress regarding: (1) the testing, production, deployment, and sale or transfer to other states or non-state actors of the Club-K cruise missile system by the Russian Federation, and (2) the coordination of allied responses to the activities related to the Club-K cruise missile system. Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to develop a strategy to detect, defend against, and defeat the Club-K cruise missile system.

(Sec. 1242) Requires DOD to submit quarterly notifications to Congress regarding the status of potential deployment of nuclear weapons by the Russian Federation onto the territory of the Ukrainian Republic. Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to develop a strategy to respond to the military threat posed by the Russian Federation deploying covered weapons systems onto the territory of the Ukrainian Republic.

(Sec. 1243) Requires the President to notify Congress regarding Russia's continued violation of or compliance with the Treaty on Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces (INF). Requires DOD to submit reports to Congress on the status of discussions with allies regarding Russia's violation of the INF Treaty. Requires the President, if Russia has not begun to return to full compliance with the INF treaty, to begin developing counterforce and countervailing capabilities and report to Congress on development and deployment.

(Sec. 1244) Extends from 30 to 90 days the time period by which the President must notify Congress after the Russian Federation submits a proposal to modify or introduce a new aircraft or sensor under the Open Skies Treaty. Requires the views of any relevant combatant commander to be provided in the assessment of the national security implications of any new aircraft or sensor proposed to be deployed by the Russian Federation under the Treaty.

(Sec. 1245) Expresses the sense of the Congress on support for Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, including support for their sovereignty, concern over military actions of the Russian Federation against these nations, and encouragement for further defense cooperation between the United States and these nations.

(Sec. 1246) Expresses the sense of Congress on support for Georgia's sovereignty and territorial integrity as well as support for continued cooperation between the United States and Georgia.

(Sec. 1247) Prohibits funds from being used to: (1) implement any action or policy that recognizes the sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters; or (2) provide assistance to a country that has taken affirmative steps to recognize or support the Russian Federation's occupation of Crimea. Permits DOD to waive the prohibition by certifying to Congress that is in the national interest.

(Sec. 1248) Prohibits funds from being used for any bilateral military-to-military contact or cooperation between the United States and Russia until DOD certifies to Congress that Russia:

 is no longer illegally occupying Ukrainian territory; is respecting the sovereignty of all Ukrainian territory; is no longer taking actions that are inconsistent with the INF Treaty; and has not sold or otherwise transferred the Club-K land attack cruise missile system to any foreign country or person during FY2015. Permits waivers and exceptions under specified circumstances.

(Sec. 1249) Prohibits the use of funds for implementing the New START Treaty until the President submits a specified certification to Congress regarding Russian activities in Ukrainian territory and compliance with specified treaties.

Subtitle F--Matters Relating to the Asia-Pacific Region

(Sec. 1251) Expresses the sense of Congress recognizing the 70th anniversary of the end of the Allied military engagement in the Pacific theater, and the end of the Second World War.

(Sec. 1252) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the consolidation of U.S. military facilities in Okinawa, Japan and that the Henoko location remains the only option for the Futenma Replacement Facility.

(Sec. 1253) Requires the President to: (1) develop an overall strategy to promote U.S. interests in the Indo-Asia-Pacific region, (2) issue a Presidential Policy Directive to relevant departments and agencies that implements the strategy, and (3) include in the budget submission a description of how the programs and projects funded in the request align with the strategy.

(Sec. 1254) Expresses the sense of Congress on the U.S. alliance with Japan, including that the United States highly values the alliance, supports recent changes in Japanese defense policy, and reaffirms its commitment to the alliance.

(Sec. 1255) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding opportunities to enhance the U.S. alliance with the Republic of Korea.

(Sec. 1256) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a copy of the policy regarding foreign disclosure or technology release of Aegis Ashore capability to allies, including Japan, that possess sea-based Aegis weapons system-equipped naval vessels.

(Sec. 1257) Requires DOD to invite Taiwan to participate in the maritime exercise known as the Rim of the Pacific Exercise if China has been invited to participate in the exercise.

Subtitle G--Other Matters

(Sec. 1261) Extends the authority of DOD to develop, manage, and execute a Non-Conventional Assisted Recovery personnel recovery program for isolated DOD, U.S. government, and other designated personnel supporting U.S. national interests worldwide. Authorizes the use of specified O&amp;M appropriations for the program.

(Sec. 1262) Amends the Arms Control and Disarmament Act to revise the requirements for the annual report on arms control compliance (also known as the Report on Adherence to and Compliance with Arms Control, Nonproliferation, and Disarmament Agreements and Commitments). Requires the Director of National Intelligence to provide, in any year in which the report is not submitted by the deadline, a report detailing inconsistent behavior by a state party to an arms control treaty or related agreement to which the United States is a party.

(Sec. 1263) Makes permanent the authority for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Special Operations Headquarters.

(Sec. 1264) Extends the authority to conduct activities to enhance the capability of foreign countries to respond to incidents involving weapons of mass destruction.

(Sec. 1265) Limits the obligation of specified RDT&amp;E funds for arms control implementation until DOD submits to Congress a report with specified information related to the Open Skies Treaty.

(Sec. 1266) Modifies the reporting requirements for the authority to support special operations to combat terrorism and increases the authorization of appropriations.

(Sec. 1267) Establishes a cooperative program with Israel to develop an anti-tunneling defense system to detect, map, and neutralize underground tunnels.

(Sec. 1268) Requires DOD to continue implementation of the U.S. Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender- Based Violence Globally and report to Congress on implementation efforts. Authorizes DOD to provide training on preventing and responding to violence against women and girls globally in conflict, post-conflict, and humanitarian relief settings.

(Sec. 1269) Authorizes DOD to supply intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities to the U.S. Southern Command to combat specified crimes; the presence and influence of Iran, Russia, and China in the Western Hemisphere; and the national security threat posed by the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), Hezbollah, or any other foreign terrorist organization in the Western Hemisphere.

(Sec. 1270) Prohibits funds from being used to support the implementation of the Arms Trade Treaty, to sustain domestic prosecutions based on any charge related to the Treaty, or to implement the Treaty until the Senate ratifies the Treaty and implementing legislation has been enacted.

(Sec. 1271) Requires the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State to jointly submit to Congress an assessment of the military capability of the Republic of Cyprus to defend against threats to its national security.

(Sec. 1272) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the defense relationship between the United States and India.

(Sec. 1273) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should exercise all available authorities as expeditiously as possible to evacuate U.S. citizens and nationals from Yemen.

(Sec. 1274) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on the impact of any significant reduction in U.S. troop levels or materiel in Europe on NATO's ability to credibly deter, resist, and, if necessary, repel external threats to any NATO member state.

(Sec. 1275) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on violence and cartel activity in Mexico and the impact on U.S. national security.

(Sec. 1276) Requires the President to report to Congress on actions taken to ensure that Qatar is preventing terrorist leaders and financiers from operating in its country.

(Sec. 1277) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should make every effort to ensure rapid responses to any military requests for assistance from Jordan.

(Sec. 1278) Requires DOD and the Department of State to jointly submit to Congress a report on efforts to combat Boko Haram and support regional allies and partners.

(Sec. 1279) Expresses the sense of Congress that it is a national security priority of the United States to support the Republic of Tunisia and to cooperate with Tunisia by providing assistance to combat the growing terrorist threat from the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) or other terrorist organizations.

(Sec. 1280) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the future of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and initiatives to enlarge NATO.

TITLE XIII--COOPERATIVE THREAT REDUCTION

(Sec. 1301) Specifies the Cooperative Threat Reduction (CTR) programs and authorizations of appropriations included in this bill and authorizes CTR funds to be available for obligation for FY2016-FY2018.

(Sec. 1302) Allocates authorizations of appropriations of funds for the CTR program in FY2016.

TITLE XIV--OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

Subtitle A--Military Programs

(Sec. 1401) Authorizes appropriations for Defense Working Capital Funds at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1402) Authorizes appropriations for the National Defense Sealift Fund at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1403) Authorizes appropriations for Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction--Defense at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1404) Authorizes appropriations for Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities--Defense-Wide at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1405) Authorizes appropriations for the Office of the Inspector General of DOD at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1406) Authorizes appropriations for the Defense Health Program at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1407) Authorizes appropriations for National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund at the levels identified in section 4501.

Subtitle B--National Defense Stockpile

(Sec. 1411) Extends the date for completion of destruction of the existing stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions.

Subtitle C--Working-Capital Funds

(Sec. 1421) Prohibits the furlough of DOD employees paid through a working capital fund unless DOD determines that the working capital fund is insolvent or there are insufficient funds in the fund to pay the labor costs of the employee. Permits a waiver for national security purposes.

(Sec. 1422) Establishes a reserve account within the Defense Working Capital Fund to provide fund managers a contingency account for sudden fluctuations in market rates for petroleum.

Subtitle D--Other Matters

(Sec. 1431) Authorizes DOD to transfer funds from the Defense Health Program to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for the Captain James A. Lovell Health Care Center.

(Sec. 1432) Authorizes appropriations for the Armed Forces Retirement Home.

TITLE XV--AUTHORIZATION OF ADDITIONAL APPROPRIATIONS FOR OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 1501) Provides that that the purpose of this title is to authorize FY2016 appropriations to provide additional funds for: (1) for overseas contingency operations being carried out by the Armed Forces, (2) operation and maintenance expenses not otherwise provided for, and (3) to support base budget requirements.

(Sec. 1502) Authorizes additional appropriations for Procurement at the levels identified in section 4102.

(Sec. 1503) Authorizes additional appropriations for Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation at the levels identified in section 4202.

(Sec. 1504) Authorizes additional appropriations for Operation and Maintenance programs at the levels identified in sections 4302 and 4303.

Prohibits funding for the Syria and Iraq Train and Equip programs from being provided to any recipient that DOD has reported as having misused provided training and equipment.

(Sec. 1505) Authorizes additional appropriations for Military Personnel at the levels identified in section 4402.

(Sec. 1506) Authorizes additional appropriations for Defense Working Capital Funds at the levels identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1507) Authorizes additional appropriations for Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities-- Defense-Wide at the level identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1508) Authorizes additional appropriations for the Office of the Inspector General at the levels identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1509) Authorizes additional appropriations for the Defense Health Program at the levels identified in section 4502.

Subtitle B--Financial Matters

(Sec. 1521) Provides that amounts authorized to be appropriated by this title are in addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated by this bill.

(Sec. 1522) Authorizes the transfer of up to $3.5 billion of the FY2016 authorizations included in this title among other FY2016 authorizations, subject to the requirements and restrictions included in section 1001 of this bill.

Subtitle C--European Reassurance Initiative and Related Matters

(Sec. 1531) States that it is the policy of the United States to continue and expand its efforts in Europe to reassure allies and partners and deter further aggression and intimidation by the Russian Government, in order to enhance security and stability in the region.

(Sec. 1532) Authorizes DOD to provide assistance and sustainment to the military and national security forces of Ukraine through FY2016, including providing lethal weapons of a defensive nature to the security forces of Ukraine. Sets forth reporting and notification requirements.

Subtitle D--Limitations, Reports, and Other Matters

(Sec. 1541) Continues the existing limitation and restrictions on the use of funds in the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund (ASFF). Requires specified funds from the ASFF to be used for the recruitment and retention of women in the Afghanistan National Security Forces, including the modification of facilities to accommodate females.

Requires DOD to submit to Congress: (1) an inventory of the facilities and services of the Afghan Ministry of Defense and the Ministry of the Interior that lack adequate resources for Afghan female service members and police, and (2) a plan to address the most significant shortcomings.

(Sec. 1542) Authorizes transfer authorities for the Joint Improvised Explosive Device (IED) Defeat Fund. Extends DOD's authority to provide training, equipment, supplies, and services to counter the flow of improvised explosive device precursor chemicals from Pakistan to Afghanistan.

Modifies the requirements for the plan for consolidation and alignment of rapid acquisition organizations to eliminate a required timeline for the consolidation of funding sources.

Repeals the prohibition on the use of FY2015 funds from the Joint IED Defeat Fund to assign personnel or contractors to combatant commands or associated military components.

(Sec. 1543) Requires GAO to report to Congress on the use of funds authorized for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XVI--STRATEGIC PROGRAMS, CYBER, AND INTELLIGENCE MATTERS

Subtitle A--Space Activities

(Sec. 1601) Requires DOD to establish and report to Congress on a unified major force program for national security space programs to prioritize national security space activities in accordance with the requirements of DOD and national security. Requires DOD to include in the annual budget submission a report on the budget for national security space programs.

(Sec. 1602) Modifies requirements for the development of a unified space and technology strategy to remove specified directions for the elements of the strategy, coordination, and reporting requirements.

(Sec. 1603) Requires DOD to use and brief Congress on a streamlined acquisition approach for the rocket propulsion system development program. Requires the approach to include tailored documentation and review processes. Provides that funds authorized for the rocket propulsion system may be used only for the development of the system, and the necessary interfaces to the launch vehicle, to replace non-allied space launch engines by 2019.

(Sec. 1604) Prohibits DOD from awarding or renewing a contract for space launch activities under the Evolved Expendable Launch Vehicle (EELV) program if the contract uses Russian engines. Prohibits DOD from modifying a specified 2013 contract if the modification increases the number of cores procured to a total of more than 35. Specifies exceptions and permits a waiver for national security if space launch services or capabilities are unable to be obtained at a reasonable price without a Russian engine.

(Sec. 1605) Limits the delegation of waiver authority regarding the purchase of global positioning user equipment to a level no lower than the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics.

(Sec. 1606) Requires the Air Force to discontinue the currently structured EELV launch capability arrangement by the later of either the date on which the obligations of the contracts have been met, or by December 31, 2020. Permits a national security waiver if Congress is notified.

Requires the Air Force to: (1) apply consistent and appropriate standards to certified EELV providers with respect to certified cost and pricing data, and audits; and (2) develop and carry out a 10-year acquisition strategy for the EELV program that meets specified criteria.

(Sec. 1607) Requires DOD to: (1) designate a senior official to procure wideband satellite communications to meet DOD requirements, and (2) submit to Congress a plan for meeting DOD requirements for satellite communications.

(Sec. 1608) Prohibits the use of specified RDT&amp;E funds for the weather satellite follow-on system until: (1) DOD briefs Congress on a plan to address DOD requirements for cloud characterization and theater weather imagery; and (2) the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff certifies to Congress that the plan will meet the requirements and not negatively affect the commanders of the combatant commands.

(Sec. 1609) Modifies the pilot program for the acquisition of commercial satellite communications services to remove the requirement that working capital funds be used.

(Sec. 1610) Prohibits DOD from relying on space-based weather data for national security purposes, if the data is provided by the governments of China or Russia or entities controlled by those governments. Requires DOD to certify to Congress that it is in compliance with this prohibition.

(Sec. 1611) Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, to conduct and submit to Congress an evaluation of the space-based infrared system to detect, track, and target, or to develop the capability to detect, track, and target, threats to the United States, deployed members of the Armed Forces, and allies.

(Sec. 1612) Requires the Commander of the U.S. Strategic Command and the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation to jointly submit to Congress a plan for the integration of overhead persistent infrared capabilities to support specified DOD missions.

(Sec. 1613) Requires DOD to evaluate and brief Congress on options for the use of current DOD assets for the purpose of rapid reconstitution of critical space-based warfighter enabling capabilities.

(Sec. 1614) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding space defense as outlined in the National Space Policy of 2010.

(Sec. 1615) Expresses the sense of Congress that a robust multi-mission space sensor network will be vital to ensuring a strong missile defense system.

Subtitle B--Defense Intelligence and Intelligence-Related Activities

(Sec. 1621) Requires DOD to designate a senior official to act as an executive agent for open source intelligence tools.

 (Sec. 1622) Modifies the waiver provisions for the requirement for maintenance and repair of defense agency facilities to be accomplished by or through a military department designated by DOD. Revises existing waiver authority for facilities for intelligence collection or special operations abroad to add a congressional notification requirement and to sunset the waiver authority at the end of 2017.

(Sec. 1623) Prohibits the use of FY2015 DOD funds in 2015 to: (1) separate the National Intelligence Program budget from the DOD budget, (2) consolidate the National Intelligence Program budget within the DOD budget, or (3) establish a new appropriations account or account structure for the National Intelligence Program budget.

(Sec. 1624) Limits the availability of funds for the Army's Distributed Common Ground System until the Army conducts and submits to Congress a review of the program planning for the system.

(Sec. 1625) Limits the availability of funds for the Special Operation Command's Distributed Common Ground System until the Special Operations Command conducts and submits to Congress a review of the program planning for the system.

(Sec. 1626) Limits the availability of funds for the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence until DOD identifies the intelligence gaps and establishes the written policy required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014.

(Sec. 1627) Includes requirements of the U.S. Special Operations Command in the content of the annual congressional briefing the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff is required to provide on intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance requirements.

(Sec. 1628) Requires the Director of National Intelligence to submit to Congress a report on how the Director ensures that National Intelligence Program budgets for the elements of the intelligence community within DOD are adequate to satisfy the national intelligence needs of DOD as required under the National Security Act of 1947.

(Sec. 1629) Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence to review the Science and Technology Research and Foreign Material Exploitation work being conducted by the intelligence elements of DOD and recommend any necessary changes and realignments.

(Sec. 1630) Requires GAO to carry out a comprehensive review of the processes and procedures for the integration of intelligence into the defense acquisition process.

Subtitle C--Cyberspace-Related Matters

(Sec. 1641) Codifies and amends requirements for contractors to report to DOD on cyber incidents and penetrations of networks and information systems. Provides liability protection for covered contractors reporting cyber incidents to DOD using the required procedures.

Subtitle D--Nuclear Forces

(Sec. 1651) Requires the Chief of Staff of the Air Force to: (1) oversee the safety, security, effectiveness, and credibility of the nuclear deterrence mission, and (2) designate a Deputy Chief of Staff to carry out specified duties related to the nuclear deterrence mission.

Requires the Secretary of the Air Force to consolidate, to the extent that the Secretary determines it is appropriate, the responsibility, authority, accountability, and resources for carrying out the nuclear deterrence mission of the Air Force.

(Sec. 1652) Requires the Council on Oversight of the National Leadership Command, Control, and Communications System to collect and assess all reports and assessments conducted by the Intelligence Community regarding foreign threats to the command, control, and communications system for the national leadership of the United States and the vulnerabilities of the system to the threats.

(Sec. 1653) Authorizes specified Missile Procurement--Air Force funds to be used for the procurement of certain commercially available parts for intercontinental ballistic missile fuzes.

(Sec. 1654) Requires DOD to brief Congress annually on the costs of forward-deploying nuclear weapons in Europe.

(Sec. 1655) Expresses the sense of Congress on the importance of cooperation and collaboration between the United States and the United Kingdom on nuclear issues.

(Sec. 1656) Expresses the sense of Congress on the activities of the Navy related to the nuclear deterrence mission.

(Sec. 1657) Prohibits funds from being used for reducing the responsiveness or alert level of U.S. intercontinental ballistic missiles, with the exception of maintenance, safety, and security activities.

(Sec. 1658) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD should submit to Congress a plan for implementing the full recommendations of the two nuclear enterprise reviews conducted and then validated by the Air Force.

(Sec. 1659) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on the justification of the number of planned nuclear-armed cruise missiles, known as the Long Range Standoff Weapon.

Subtitle E--Missile Defense Programs

(Sec. 1661) Prohibits the use of funds to provide specified missile defense information to the Russian Federation. Provides the President with a single use waiver to provide Russia with information regarding ballistic missile early warning if specified officials certify that the information is required because of a failure of the early warning system of Russia.

(Sec. 1662) Prohibits the use of funds to integrate a missile defense system of the People's Republic of China into any U.S. missile defense system.

(Sec. 1663) Prohibits funds authorized for U.S contributions to NATO from being used to integrate a missile defense system of the Russian Federation into any missile defense system of the United States or NATO.

(Sec. 1664) Prohibits the use of funds for military construction for the Long-Range Discriminating Radar until: (1) the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation submits a cost assessment to Congress; (2) the Commander, U.S. Strategic Command and the Commander, U.S. Northern Command jointly certify that the proposed site for the LRDR best supports missile defense and space situational awareness and is the most cost-effective option; and (3) the certification has been submitted to Congress for at least 60 days.

(Sec. 1665) Prohibits funds from being used for specified components and capabilities of the Patriot air and missile defense program of the Army until: (1) an analysis of alternatives has been submitted to Congress, and (2) the Under Secretary of Defense Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics certifies that the expenditure of funds for the program is consistent with the analysis.

(Sec. 1666) Requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to ensure the interoperability and integration of certain air and missile defense systems.

Requires the Missile Defense Agency (MDA) and the Army to conduct at least one intercept or flight test per year that demonstrates interoperable and integrated air and missile defense capability. Permits a waiver if it will not negatively affect demonstrating interoperability and integration.

(Sec. 1667) Requires the Commanders of the U.S. European, Central, and Pacific Commands to submit to the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff an assessment of the opportunities for integration and interoperability of air and missile defenses of the United States with capabilities of U.S. allies.

Requires the Secretary and the Chairman to: (1) submit the assessments to Congress; (2) carry out the planning, risk assessments, policy developments, and concepts of operations necessary to assure the integration, interoperability, and command-and-control of U.S. and allied air and missile defenses; and (3) provide quarterly updates to Congress.

(Sec. 1668) Requires DOD to: (1) ensure that the Aegis Ashore sites to be deployed in Poland and Romania have anti-air warfare capabilities; (2) evaluate the feasibility, benefit, and cost of using the Evolved Sea Sparrow Missile or the Standard Missile 2 in providing the capability; (3) ensure that a Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) battery is available for rotational deployment to the U.S. European Command area of responsibility; (4) examine sites to pre-position the THAAD battery if necessary for military requirements; and (5) examine at least three sites for the deployment of a THAAD battery and three sites for the deployment of a Patriot air and missile defense battery, if necessary.

(Sec. 1669) Authorizes appropriations to be provided to Israel for the Iron Dome short-range rocket defense system. Requires the funds to be subject to the "Agreement Between the Department of Defense of the United States of America and the Ministry of Defense of the State of Israel Concerning Iron Dome Defense System Procurement." Requires DOD to submit to Congress prior to obligating funds: (1) a certification that the Agreement is being successfully implemented, and (2) an assessment of risks relating to the implementation of the Agreement.

(Sec. 1670) Authorizes appropriations for procurement and coproduction of the Israeli David's Sling Weapons System and the Arrow 3 Upper Tier missile defense system, subject to specified terms and conditions.

(Sec. 1671) Requires the MDA to develop and deploy a highly reliable multiple-object kill vehicle for the ground-based midcourse defense system using best acquisition practices.

(Sec. 1672) Requires DOD to:

 prioritize technology investments to develop and field a boost phase missile defense system by FY2022; ensure that the system can benefit multiple warfighter requirements; continue development of high-energy lasers and high-power microwave systems as part of a layered architecture to defend ships and theater bases against air and cruise missile strikes; and encourage collaboration among the military departments and the DARPA with respect to high energy laser efforts. Requires the MDA to establish a senior level advisory group to recommend technologies for use as a boost phase missile defense layer and brief Congress on the recommendations.

(Sec. 1673) Requires the Navy to: (1) relocate the sea-based X-band radar (SBX) to a new homeport on the East Coast of the United States by December 31, 2020, and (2) ensure that the vessel has an at-sea capability of at least 120 days per year.

Requires the MDA to: (1) begin the studies and evaluations necessary for the relocation within 60 days of enactment of this bill, and (2) certify, prior to executing the relocation, that the relocation will not impact the missile defense of Hawaii.

(Sec. 1674) Requires the MDA to evaluate and submit to Congress potential options for fielding a medium range ballistic missile defense sensor to defend Hawaii.

(Sec. 1675) Requires the MDA to commence the concept definition, design, research, development, and engineering evaluation of a space-based ballistic missile intercept and defeat layer to the ballistic missile defense system.

(Sec. 1676) Requires the Director of the MDA to evaluate the role, feasibility, cost, and cost benefit of additional Aegis Ashore sites and upgrades to current ballistic missile defense system sensors to offset capacity demands on current Aegis ships, Aegis Ashore sites, and Patriot and Terminal High Altitude Area Defense capability and to meet the requirements of the combatant commanders.

Require the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy and the Secretary of State to jointly identify any obstacles to foreign military sales of Aegis Ashore or co-financing of additional Aegis Ashore sites.

Requires the President to seek to enter into host nation agreements for Aegis Ashore sites and co-financing and co-development opportunities as appropriate if the sites meet the requirements of the combatant commanders.

(Sec. 1677) Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to brief Congress on the military requirement for left-of-launch capability and any current capability gaps in meeting the requirement. Requires the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence to brief Congress on the plan to develop and procure the left-of-launch capabilities.

(Sec. 1678) Requires the Director of the MDA to designate the preferred U.S. location for an additional missile defense site within 30 days of publication of the draft environmental impact statements required by National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013.

(Sec. 1679) Requires the Air Force to submit to Congress a report examining the costs associated with extending the life of the Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missile compared to the costs associated with procuring a new ground based strategic deterrent.

Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 

DIVISION B--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION AUTHORIZATIONS

(Sec. 2002) Provides that all authorizations contained in titles XXI through XXVII and title XXIX for military construction projects, land acquisition, family housing projects and facilities, and contributions to the NATO Security Investment Program shall expire on the later of October 1, 2018, or the date of the enactment of an Act authorizing funds for military construction for FY2019. Includes an exception for funds that have been obligated prior to the later of the two dates.

(Sec. 2003) Provides that titles XXI, XXII, XXIII, XXIV, XXV, XXVI, XXVII, and XXIX of this bill shall take effect on October 1, 2015, or the date of enactment of this bill, whichever is later.

TITLE XXI--ARMY MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2101) Authorizes specified Army construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2102) Authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Army.

(Sec. 2103) Authorizes the Army to make improvements to existing units of family housing.

(Sec. 2104) Authorizes appropriations for Army military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2105) Modifies the authorization for the construction of a Cadet barracks building at the U.S. Military Academy in New York.

(Sec. 2106) Extends the authorizations for specified FY2012 projects.

(Sec. 2107) Extends the authorizations for specified FY2013 projects.

(Sec. 2108) Authorizes a military construction project to construct a multi-sport athletic field and track, perimeter road, and fencing and acquire land adjacent to the existing Sterrebeek Dependent School site to allow relocation of Army functions to the site in support of the European Infrastructure Consolidation effort.

Authorizes a project to construct a vehicle bridge and traffic circle to facilitate traffic flow to and from the Medical Center at Rhine Ordnance Barracks, Germany. Permits the Army to use available host-nation payment-in-kind funding for the project

TITLE XXII--NAVY MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2201) Authorizes specified Navy construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2202) Authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Navy.

(Sec. 2203) Authorizes the Navy to make improvements to existing units of family housing.

(Sec. 2204) Authorizes appropriations for Navy military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2205) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2012 projects.

(Sec. 2206) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2013 projects.

(Sec. 2207) Provides special conveyance authority to the Navy for two fire and emergency response stations as part of the land acquisition agreement to support emergency services for the expansion of Townsend Bombing Range to support Marine Corps Air Station, Beaufort, Georgia.

TITLE XXIII--AIR FORCE MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2301) Authorizes specified Air Force construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2302) Authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Air Force.

(Sec. 2303) Authorizes the Air Force to make improvements to existing units of family housing.

(Sec. 2304) Authorizes appropriations for Air Force military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2305) Modifies the authorization for construction of a ground control tower at Hickam Air Force Base, Hawaii.

(Sec. 2306) Modifies the authorization for construction of a Guardian Angel Operations Facility at Royal Air Force Lakenheath, United Kingdom.

(Sec. 2307) Modifies the authorization for construction of a KC-46A Alter Composite Maintenance Shop at McConnell Air Force Base, Kansas.

(Sec. 2308) Extends the authorization for a specified project at Sigonella Naval Air Station, Italy.

(Sec. 2309) Extends the authorization for a specified project at Lajes Field, Portugal.

(Sec. 2310) Prohibits the Air Force from using funds authorized by this title for the construction of Joint Intelligence Analysis Complex Consolidation, Phase 2, at Royal Air Force Croughton, United Kingdom, until the Air Force submits to Congress a report on the continuity of operations considerations for the critical communications and intelligence capabilities located at or being located to Royal Air Force Croughton.

Limits actions to realign forces at Lajes Air Force Base, Azores, until DOD certifies that Lajes Air Force Base is not an optimal location for the Joint Intelligence Analysis Complex, or any of the critical communications or intelligence capabilities considered in the continuity of operations planning.

TITLE XXIV--DEFENSE AGENCIES MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2401) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for defense agencies.

(Sec. 2402) Authorizes DOD to carry out specified energy conservation projects, subject to specified restrictions.

(Sec. 2403) Authorizes appropriations for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of defense agencies at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2404) Modifies the authorization for construction of the High Performance Computing Center at Fort Meade, Maryland.

(Sec. 2405) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2012 projects.

(Sec. 2406) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2013 projects.

(Sec. 2407) Modifies the authorization for construction of an Ambulatory Care Center for Fort Knox, Kentucky.

TITLE XXV--NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY ORGANIZATION SECURITY INVESTMENT PROGRAM

(Sec. 2501) Authorizes DOD to make specified contributions to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security equal to the sum of amount authorized in section 2502 and the amount collected from NATO for construction previously financed by the United States.

(Sec. 2502) Authorizes appropriations for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program at the levels identified in section 4601.

TITLE XXVI--GUARD AND RESERVE FORCES FACILITIES

Subtitle A--Project Authorizations and Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 2601) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Army National Guard.

(Sec. 2602) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Army Reserve.

(Sec. 2603) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Navy Reserve and Marine Corps Reserve.

(Sec. 2604) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Air National Guard.

 (Sec. 2605) Authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Air Force Reserve.

(Sec. 2606) Authorize appropriations for the National Guard and Reserve military construction at the levels identified in section 4601.

Subtitle B--Other Matters

(Sec. 2611) Authorizes the Army to modify the scope of the authorization for construction of the Army Reserve Center for Aberdeen Proving Ground, Maryland.

(Sec. 2612) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2012 projects.

(Sec. 2613) Extends the authorizations of specified FY2013 projects.

TITLE XXVII--BASE REALIGNMENT AND CLOSURE ACTIVITIES

(Sec. 2701) Authorizes appropriations for ongoing Base Realignment and Closure activities at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2702) States that nothing in this bill authorizes an additional Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) round.

TITLE XXVIII--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION GENERAL PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing Changes

(Sec. 2801) Aligns the thresholds for congressional notification of reserve facility expenditures and contributions with the thresholds for minor construction and repair projects.

(Sec. 2802) Authorizes DOD to accept and use contributions from Kuwait for construction, maintenance, and repair projects within Kuwait that are mutually beneficial to DOD and the Kuwait military forces, subject to congressional notification requirements and an annual obligation limit.

(Sec. 2803 Authorizes DOD to use specified funds to carry out a defense laboratory modernization pilot program.

(Sec. 2804) Authorizes minor military construction projects for child development program facilities, subject to specified requirements.

(Sec. 2805) Expresses the sense of Congress that DOD should take into consideration, when prioritizing base housing projects, commuting times for base personnel and land available for development on the base.

Subtitle B--Real Property and Facilities Administration

(Sec. 2811) Authorizes the military service academies to accept a gift of real property conditioned upon the naming of the property if the acceptance and naming would not reflect unfavorably on the United States, and the real property has not otherwise been named by an act of Congress.

(Sec. 2812) Requires the Secretary concerned to consult with the chief executive officer of the state, district, or territory regarding major defense land acquisitions.

(Sec. 2813) Modifies the requirements for DOD's existing overseas basing report to add a strategic summary for each main operating base, forward operating site, or cooperative security location within the U.S. Central Command and U.S. Africa Command areas of responsibility.

(Sec. 2814) Requires DOD to submit with the annual budget request a 20-year force structure plan for each of the military services and a comprehensive inventory of worldwide infrastructure.

(Sec. 2815) Permits the Secretary concerned to authorize military manufacturing arsenal leases or contracts for terms of up to 25 years if it will promote the national defense or is in the public interest for specified purposes.

Subtitle C--Provisions Related to Asia-Pacific Military Realignment

(Sec. 2821) Amends restrictions on the development of civilian infrastructure on Guam to support the realignment of Marine Corps Forces in the Asia-Pacific region. Allows the use of funds for infrastructure projects identified in the report of the Economic Adjustment Committee required by the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014.

(Sec. 2822) Requires DOD to submit to Congress an annual report that addresses the total amount of received and anticipated contributions from Japan to the Support for United States Relocation to Guam Account.

Subtitle D--Land Conveyances

(Sec. 2831) Authorizes a land exchange involving a parcel of real property under the jurisdiction of the Army on the site of the former Mare Island Naval Shipyard, Vallejo, California, in the event that a current real property exchange process is unsuccessful.

(Sec. 2832) Authorizes the Navy to convey a parcel of real property containing Navy Outlying Landing Field Site 8 in Escambia County, Florida, to Escambia County in exchange for a parcel of property that is suitable for use as a Navy outlying landing field to replace Navy Outlying Landing Field Site 8.

(Sec. 2833) Authorizes the Army to release the rights and the reversionary interests reserved by the United States for a parcel of land in El Paso, Texas, to authorize Texas to sell a portion of the property and use all proceeds from the sale to fund improvements or repairs for the National Guard facilities on the remainder of the property.

(Sec. 2834) Authorizes the Army to release property interests and terms and conditions imposed in connection with a parcel of property at Camp Villere, Louisiana that the United States conveyed to Louisiana for National Guard purposes.

Requires Louisiana to: (1) transfer the property from the Louisiana Military Department to the Louisiana Agricultural Finance Authority, and (2) Make available to the Louisiana Military Department real property to replace the transferred parcel that is suitable for use for National Guard training and operational support for emergency management and homeland defense activities.

(Sec. 2835) Authorizes the Department of the Interior to convey, without consideration, public land at the former Campion Air Force Station, Alaska to the town of Galena, Alaska to permit the town to use the land for public purposes.

Subtitle E--Military Land Withdrawals

(Sec. 2841) Provides for the withdrawal and reservation of additional public land in San Bernardino County, California, to support operations at Naval Air Weapons Station China Lake, California.

 (Sec. 2842) Extends the public lands withdrawn for military purposes listed in the Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1999 until the Secretary of the military department determines a military purpose does not exist, or the Secretary of Interior permanently transfers the administrative jurisdiction to the Secretary of the military department concerned.

Subtitle F--Military Memorials, Monuments, and Museums

(Sec. 2851) Changes the name of the John W. Berry, Sr. Wright Brothers Aviation Center, in Dayton, Ohio, to the John W. Berry, Sr. Wright Brothers National Museum.

(Sec. 2852) Extends the authority to establish a commemorative work on federal land in the District of Columbia and its environs to honor Brigadier General Francis Marion.

(Sec. 2853) Prohibits the designation of federal property as a National Historic Landmark or for nomination to the World Heritage List if the head of the agency managing the property objects for reasons of national security. Authorizes the expedited removal of federal property listed on the National Register of Historic Places if the managing agency of the property submits a request to the Secretary of Interior for removal for national security.

Subtitle G--Other Matters

(Sec. 2861) Requires DOD to modify specified guidance and specifications for pavement markings to permit the use of the Type III category of retro-reflective beads. Requires the determination of the category of retro-reflective beads used on air-fields to be made on an installation-by-installation basis based on local conditions and the life-cycle maintenance costs of the pavement markings.

(Sec. 2862) Delays findings by the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the Greater Sage Grouse under the Endangered Species Act through September 30, 2025. Prohibits Interior or the Department of Agriculture from amending any federal resource management plans affecting the Greater Sage Grouse in a state in which the governor has notified the Secretaries that a state management plan is in place.

(Sec. 2863) Provides that the establishment or expansion of a national monument by the President on land located beneath or associated with a Military Operations Area shall not be construed to prohibit or constrain any activities on or above the land conducted by DOD or other federal agencies for national security purposes.

(Sec. 2864) Renames the Captain William Wylie Galt Great Falls Armed Forces Readiness Center in Great Falls, Montana, as the Captain John E. Moran and Captain William Wylie Galt Armed Forces Reserve Center.

(Sec. 2865) Prohibits the lesser prairie chicken from being treated as a threatened or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 prior to January 31, 2021.

Prohibits the lesser prairie chicken from being treated as a threatened or endangered species on or after January 31, 2021, unless the Department of the Interior publishes a determination, based on the totality of the scientific evidence, that goals established by the Range-Wide Plan have not been achieved. (The Range-Wide Plan is the Lesser Prairie-Chicken Range-Wide Conservation Plan of the Western Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies, as endorsed by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service on October 23, 2013.)

(Sec. 2866) Prohibits the American burying beetle from being listed as a threatened or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

TITLE XXIX--OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2901) Authorizes specified overseas contingency operations construction and land acquisition projects for the Army.

(Sec. 2902) Authorizes specified overseas contingency operations construction and land acquisition projects for the Navy.

(Sec. 2903) Authorizes specified overseas contingency operations construction and land acquisition projects for the Air Force.

(Sec. 2904) Authorizes specified overseas contingency operations construction and land acquisition projects for defense agencies.

(Sec. 2905) Authorizes appropriations for overseas contingency operations military construction at the levels identified in section 4602.

DIVISION C--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY AUTHORIZATIONS AND OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

TITLE XXXI--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY PROGRAMS

Subtitle A--National Security Programs Authorizations

(Sec. 3101) Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) at the levels identified in section 4701 of division D of this Act. Authorizes a new plant project for the NNSA at the Los Alamos National Laboratory in New Mexico.

(Sec. 3102) Authorizes appropriations to DOE for defense environmental cleanup activities at the levels identified in section 4701 of this bill.

(Sec. 3103) Authorizes to DOE for other defense activities in carrying out programs as specified in section 4701 of this bill.

(Sec. 3104) Authorizes appropriations to DOE for nuclear energy as specified in section 4701 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations

(Sec. 3111) Amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act to authorize personnel levels for the NNSA.

(Sec. 3112) Authorizes contractor personnel levels for the NNSA and sets forth reporting requirements related to personnel levels.

(Sec. 3113) Requires the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator for Nuclear Security to: (1) submit to Congress specified details regarding employees involved in nuclear security whose security clearances were revoked, (2) notify Congress whenever a covered employee involved in nuclear security is terminated or removed and reassigned, and (3) certify to Congress that they possess the authorities needed to terminate an employee for cause relating to improper program management.

Prohibits bonuses from being paid to employees during the one-year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary or the Administrator determines that the employee committed improper program management, subject to a waiver.

Requires the Secretary and the Administrator to: (1) certify to Congress that specified covered projects are being carried out on time, on budget, and within the planned scope of the project, while protecting health, safety, and security, and (2) provide specified details and contractual options regarding projects that could not be certified.

(Sec. 3114) Requires cost benefit analyses submitted after awarding a contract to manage and operate an NNSA facility to include a description of the factors considered and processes used to determine (1) whether to compete or extend a contract to manage and operate a facility of the nuclear security enterprise; and (2) whether and which activities at the facility should be covered under the management and operating contract rather than under a different contract.

(Sec. 3115) Amends the Atomic Energy Defense Act to establish the U.S. policy to sustain, enhance, and continually exercise all capabilities required to conceptualize, study, design, develop, engineer, certify, produce, and deploy nuclear weapons to ensure the nuclear deterrent of the United States remains safe, secure, reliable, credible, and responsive. Requires DOE to carry out a program in parallel with the stockpile stewardship stockpile management programs to fulfill this policy and specifies objectives for the program.

(Sec. 3116) Requires DOE to carry out construction and program support activities for the Mixed Oxide (MOX) Fuel Fabrication Facility with any funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for this purpose. Requires DOE to include in the budget justification materials an updated performance baseline for construction and project support activities relating to the MOX facility.

(Sec. 3117) Prohibits the use of NNSA funds for the research and development, installation, or sustainment of fixed site radiological portal monitors or equipment for use in foreign countries, with the exception of mobile radiological inspection equipment.

(Sec. 3118) Prohibits the use of funds made available for defense nuclear nonproliferation activities from being used to enter into a contract with, or otherwise provide assistance to, the Russian Federation. Permits a national security waiver.

(Sec. 3119) Requires that, prior to NNSA approval of certain transfers of civil nuclear technology for a foreign state with a nuclear naval propulsion program that: (1) the Director of National Intelligence and the Chief of Naval Operations submit to Congress an assessment of the risks and likely consequences of the diversion of the technology, and (2) the NNSA certify to Congress that there is sufficient diversion control and the transfer presents a minimal risk of diversion to a military program that would degrade the technical advantage of the United States.

(Sec. 3120) Prohibits funds authorized for the NNSA's Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation program from being used to develop nonproliferation or arms control verification or monitoring technologies beyond Technology Readiness Level 5 (TRL 5) unless DOE certifies that the technologies are being developed to fulfill the rights or obligations of the United States under an arms control treaty or agreement requiring verification or monitoring. Permits a waiver for national security.

(Sec. 3121) Limits the availability of funds for certain nuclear weapons dismantlement and disposition activities.

(Sec. 3122) Requires DOE to ensure the use of best practices in analyzing alternatives and estimating costs for capital asset projects and nuclear weapon life extension programs.

(Sec. 3123) Specifies the cost threshold for nuclear weapons systems undergoing life extensions that are covered by requirements for Selected Acquisition Reports and independent cost estimates.

Subtitle C--Plans and Reports

(Sec. 3131) Requires DOE to conduct and submit to Congress a root cause assessment when certain programs experience a significant cost overrun.

(Sec. 3132) Extends and modifies requirements for annual reports on nuclear nonproliferation to require DOD to provide details regarding highly-enriched uranium and separated plutonium around the world that is obligated by the United States.

(Sec. 3133) Requires the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator for Nuclear Security to jointly establish a team of senior officials to implement a plan to reform governance and management to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the nuclear security enterprise.

(Sec. 3134) Requires the Direction of National Intelligence to report to Congress annually on nuclear proliferation risks and nuclear nonproliferation opportunities.

(Sec. 3135) Requires the Administrator for Nuclear Security to seek to enter into a contract with the JASON Defense Advisory Panel to review certain laboratory-directed research and development programs authorized under Atomic Energy Defense Act. Requires GAO to brief Congress on the funding limits and the number of personnel for the programs.

(Sec. 3136) Requires DOE to establish a pilot program to establish a microlab that is located near a national laboratory and that is accessible to the public for: (1) enhancing collaboration with regional research groups, (2) accelerating technology transfer from national laboratories to the marketplace, and (3) promoting regional workforce development through science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) instruction and training.

Subtitle D--Other Matters

(Sec. 3141) Requires DOE to carry out a plan for the Administrator for Nuclear Security to transfer to the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management the responsibility for decontaminating and decommissioning NNSA facilities that are not operational and meet the requirements of the Office of Environmental Management for the transfer.

(Sec. 3142) Requires specified funds to be made available for initial planning and early research and development of an advanced naval nuclear fuel system based on low-enriched uranium. Sets forth reporting requirements.

(Sec. 3143) Requires the Chairman of the Nuclear Weapons Council to brief Congress on the annual plutonium pit production capacity requirement of the nuclear security enterprise.

(Sec. 3144) Requires the NNSA to: (1) submit to Congress the analysis of alternatives conducted for the Mobile Guardian Transporter program, and (2) contract with a federally funded research and development center for an independent assessment of the analysis.

(Sec. 3145) Requires the President to develop, pursue, and brief Congress on a strategy to address the risks to the goals and policies of the United States regarding nuclear nonproliferation that are caused by the increased use of additive manufacture technology (commonly referred to as 3D printing).

TITLE XXXII--DEFENSE NUCLEAR FACILITIES SAFETY BOARD

(Sec. 3201) Authorizes appropriations for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.

(Sec. 3202) Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide that: (1) the Chairman of the Defense Nuclear Facilities Board may not withhold from members of the Board certain information regarding the Board's functions, powers, and mission; and (2) the Chairman of the Board, subject to the approval of the Board, may appoint and remove specified senior employees of the Board.

TITLE XXXIV--NAVAL PETROLEUM RESERVES

(Sec. 3401) Authorizes appropriations for the operation and maintenance of the Naval Petroleum Reserves.

TITLE XXXV--MARITIME ADMINISTRATION

(Sec. 3501) Authorizes appropriations for the national security aspects of the Merchant Marine.

(Sec. 3502) Expresses the sense of Congress that dedicated and enhanced support is necessary to stabilize and preserve the Maritime Security Fleet program.

(Sec. 3503) Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reflect the transfer of the Maritime Administration from the Department of Commerce to the Department of Transportation.

(Sec. 3504) Requires the U.S. Coast Guard to rely on certifications from the American Bureau of Shipping or another classification society accepted by the Secretary of Transportation in determining the eligibility of a vessel to receive a certificate of inspection.

(Sec. 3505) Increases the authorization of appropriations for FY2016 payments to contractors for each maritime security fleet vessel covered by an operating agreement. Increases the authorization of appropriations for expenses to maintain and preserve a United States-flag merchant marine to serve the national security needs of the United States.

(Sec. 3506) Permits the Maritime Administrator to accept a gift of money from the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy Alumni Association and Foundation, Inc. for the purpose of renovating Melville Hall on the campus of the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy.

DIVISION D--FUNDING TABLES

(Sec. 4001) Provides for the allocation of funds among programs, projects, and activities in accordance with the tables in division D of this bill, subject to reprogramming requirements.

TITLE XLI--PROCUREMENT

(Sec. 4101) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Procurement.

(Sec. 4102) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Procurement for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XLII--RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, TEST, AND EVALUATION

(Sec. 4201) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation.

(Sec. 4202) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XLIII--OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE

(Sec. 4301) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Operation and Maintenance.

(Sec. 4302) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Operation and Maintenance for Overseas Contingency Operations.

(Sec. 4303) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Operation and Maintenance for Overseas Contingency Operations for base requirements.

TITLE XLIV--MILITARY PERSONNEL

 (Sec. 4401) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Military Personnel.

(Sec. 4402) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Military Personnel for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XLV--OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

(Sec. 4501) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for other specified authorizations, including: the Working Capital Fund, the National Defense Sealift Fund, the National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund, Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, the Office of the Inspector General, and the Defense Health Program.

(Sec. 4502) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for the Working Capital Fund, Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, the Office of the Inspector General, and the Defense Health Program for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XLVI--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 4601) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Military Construction.

(Sec. 4602) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Military Construction for Overseas Contingency Operations.

TITLE XLVII--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY PROGRAMS

(Sec. 4701) Sets forth amounts requested and authorized for Department of Energy National Security Programs.</summary>
</bill>
