<bill session="114" type="h" number="1753" updated="2015-06-27T06:48:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Cyberspace Coordination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a National Office for Cyberspace, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412616" joined="2015-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2015--Introduced.
Executive Cyberspace Coordination Act of 2015

This bill establishes the National Office for Cyberspace within the Executive Office of the President, to be headed by a Director. The Office shall serve as the principal office for coordinating issues relating to cyberspace, including achieving an assured, reliable, secure, and survivable information infrastructure while promoting national economic interests, security, and civil liberties. The bill defines "information infrastructure" as the underlying framework that information systems and assets rely on to process, store, or transmit information electronically.

The bill assigns new duties to the Director, including: (1) reviewing at least annually, and approving or disapproving, agency information security programs; (2) coordinating information security training for federal employees with the Office of Personnel Management; and (3) ensuring the adequacy of protections for privacy and civil liberties. The head of each agency must submit to the Director an annual budget relating to the protection of information infrastructure for the agency, which shall include a review of any threats to information technology for such agency and a plan to secure the information infrastructure for such agency based on threats to information technology.</summary>
</bill>
