<bill session="114" type="h" number="1801" updated="2015-07-30T04:48:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Financial Literacy and Economic Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a tax credit for providing programs to kindergarten, elementary, and secondary students that promote economic and financial literacy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2015-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412637" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400179" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412638" joined="2015-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="412432" joined="2015-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2015--Introduced.
Promoting Financial Literacy and Economic Opportunity Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow up to 20 for-profit organizations in any taxable year a business-related tax credit for 50% of the amount paid or incurred to carry out activities to improve the quality of student understanding of personal finance and economics. The Department of the Treasury shall determine which for-profit organizations are eligible for the credit, ensuring that a majority of credit recipients are: (1) either a socially and economically disadvantaged small business concern, a small business concern owned and controlled by women, or a small business concern that is at least 51% owned by veterans, or (2) do not have more than $60 billion in assets. In determining the eligibility of a for-profit organization, Treasury shall give priority to organizations that have programs serving either urban or rural underserved areas.</summary>
</bill>
