<bill session="114" type="h" number="1811" updated="2015-08-22T06:34:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program, to provide for cash relief for years for which annual COLAs do not take effect under certain cash benefit programs, and to provide for Social Security benefit protection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412571" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412307" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412212" joined="2015-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2015-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="s" number="960"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1940"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/15/2015--Introduced.
Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act

 Directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor to prepare and publish for each calendar month a Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI-EC) that indicates changes over time in consumption expenditures typical for individuals in the United States age 62 or older.

Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to make the CPI-EC the applicable Consumer Price Index for computation of cost-of-living increases in OASDI benefits for such individuals.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe special rules for the determination of wages and self-employment income above the contribution and benefit base after 2015.

Amends SSAct title II to include surplus average indexed monthly earnings in the determination of primary OASDI amounts.</summary>
</bill>
