<bill session="114" type="h" number="2082" updated="2015-07-24T04:48:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM K to Career Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for loan forgiveness for STEM teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412514"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412637" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412327" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412612" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412286" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412318" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2015--Introduced.
STEM K to Career Act

This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to require the Department of Education to forgive student loan obligations of borrowers employed as full-time teachers of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) in elementary or secondary schools in which the number of low-income children exceeds a certain percentage.

Portions of the student loan debt, including interest, will be forgiven on the basis of years of service, with 100% forgiven for five years of teacher service.

 The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) an increased tax deduction for expenses by elementary and secondary school teachers for STEM education supplies; (2) a tax credit for the employment of STEM interns; and (3) a tax credit for employment of individuals who participated in an apprenticeship program in a STEM field, with the amount determined according to the degree of completion of a program.

 Beginning with FY2016, an institution of higher education must use at least 7% of federal work-study funds granted under HEA to compensate students employed in STEM fields.</summary>
</bill>
