<bill session="114" type="h" number="2151" updated="2015-06-27T06:55:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Oversight and Accountability in Medicaid Non-DSH Supplemental Payments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to improve the calculation, oversight, and accountability of non-DSH supplemental payments under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/2015--Introduced.
Improving Oversight and Accountability in Medicaid Non-DSH Supplemental Payments Act 

This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) issue guidance to states that identifies permissible methods for calculation of non-DSH (disproportionate share) supplemental payments to providers, (2) establish annual reporting requirements for states making non-DSH supplemental payments, and (3) establish requirements for states making non-DSH supplemental payments to conduct and submit to the Secretary an annual independent certified audit.

No federal payment under Medicaid may be made to a state for any expenditures to make non-DSH supplemental payments unless the state complies with the reporting and auditing requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
