<bill session="114" type="h" number="2218" updated="2015-07-15T04:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renovate and Enhance Veterans' Meeting Halls and Posts Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REVAMP Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to set-aside community development block grant amounts in each fiscal year for grants to local chapters of veterans service organizations for rehabilitation of, and technology for, their facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412635" joined="2015-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400641" joined="2015-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412523" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412647" joined="2015-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412570" joined="2015-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2015-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/2015--Introduced.
Renovate and Enhance Veterans' Meeting Halls and Posts Act of 2015 or REVAMP Act of 2015

 Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to require the Department of Housing and Urban Development to make competitive grants to eligible veterans service organizations for: (1) repairs or rehabilitation of their existing facilities, and (2) acquiring or upgrading computers and technology for such facilities.

Defines "eligible veterans service organization" as: (1) a tax-exempt entity organized on a local or area basis; and (2) a tax-exempt local or area chapter, post, or other unit of a national, regional, statewide, or other larger entity of which local or area chapters, posts, or units are members (but not any such national, regional, statewide, or other larger entity itself).

 Prohibits an eligible veterans service organization from receiving such grant amounts, for any single fiscal year, in an amount exceeding the lesser of: (1) the aggregate cost of the proposed activities and uses for which the grant amounts will be used, or (2) $200,000.

Makes a grant recipient ineligible to receive another such grant for any of the five succeeding fiscal years.

Prohibits the use of such grants for construction or acquisition of a new facility.</summary>
</bill>
