<bill session="114" type="h" number="2313" updated="2015-07-25T06:38:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Research for Hydrocephalus Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance and expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of hydrocephalus, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E782"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2015--Introduced.
Advancing Research for Hydrocephalus Act of 2015

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to: (1) enhance and expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of hydrocephalus (a condition in which fluid accumulates in the brain); and (2) incorporate information obtained through those activities into a National Hydrocephalus Surveillance System. Requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to ensure that the System facilitates further research on hydrocephalus.

Requires HHS to provide for the collection and storage of information on hydrocephalus, including the incidence, prevalence, and other information, to the extent practicable.

Requires HHS to: (1) make information and analysis in the System available to the public, including researchers; and (2) ensure that privacy and security protections applicable to the System are at least as stringent as the protections under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.</summary>
</bill>
