<bill session="114" type="h" number="2351" updated="2015-08-01T06:39:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Professional Boxing Safety Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 to provide additional safety standards for professional boxing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2015-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2015-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-15">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2015--Introduced.
Professional Boxing Safety Enhancement Act of 2015

Amends the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 to repeal a provision allowing a professional boxing match to meet an alternative requirement in effect under regulations of a boxing commission that provides protection of the health and safety of boxers and that is equivalent to requirements otherwise provided under such Act.

Requires a boxer to provide with the application for a boxing license or for renewal of such license an original or certified copy of the results of medical tests that: (1) were performed by a laboratory during the calendar year for which the license is being issued or no earlier than 30 days before the application is submitted, and (2) show that the boxer is not infected with the human immunodeficiency virus or the hepatitis virus.

Requires an ambulance and emergency medical personnel with appropriate resuscitation equipment (currently, one or the other) to be continuously present on site.</summary>
</bill>
