<bill session="114" type="h" number="2407" updated="2015-08-22T06:39:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Milk Nutrition Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reverse declining milk consumption in schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412541" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412563" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412193" joined="2015-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2015-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412661" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412454" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412444" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412465" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2015-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412311" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2015-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3648"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2015--Introduced.
School Milk Nutrition Act of 2015 

This bill revises the requirements for milk provided by the National School Lunch Program (NSLP) and other Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs.

The bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the milk offered to students participating in the NSLP to include low-fat flavored milk containing no more than 150 calories per 8-ounce serving.

For students who cannot consume fluid milk because of a medical or other dietary need, schools may offer a nondairy beverage that is nutritionally equivalent to low-fat milk and meets USDA nutritional standards, including fortification of calcium, protein, vitamin A, vitamin D, magnesium, phosphorus, potassium, riboflavin, and vitamin B-12. (Under current law, the substitute is only required to include fortification of calcium, protein, vitamin A, and vitamin D to levels found in cow's milk.)

In establishing national school nutritional standards, USDA must provide that containers of all beverages sold in schools have the same maximum volume.

USDA must also: (1) study and report to Congress on recent trends in fluid milk consumption in schools; (2) carry out a pilot program to test and demonstrate strategies by which schools can increase the consumption of fluid milk; (3) make lactose-free milk with an extended shelf life available to schools; and (4) allow women participating in the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) to receive reduced fat milk for themselves and their children upon request.</summary>
</bill>
