<bill session="114" type="h" number="2431" updated="2015-08-08T06:39:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">On-the-Job Training Tax Credit Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit against tax for job training expenses of employers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412517" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="412638" joined="2015-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="2015-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412514" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="412617" joined="2015-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3544"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2015--Introduced.
On-the-Job Training Tax Credit Act of 2015

 Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow&#160;employers who employ not more than 500 full-time employees during the taxable year an on-the-job training tax credit equal to the lesser of: 50% of the job training program&#160;expenditures for a full-time&#160;employee participating in a qualified training program, or $5,000.

Defines "qualified training program" as a written plan of study and training that is either: (1) an apprenticeship program registered and certified with the Department of Labor under the National Apprenticeship Act; (2) a program licensed, registered, or certified by the workforce investment board or apprenticeship agency or council of a state or administered in compliance with state apprenticeship laws; (3) a program conducted by a vocational or technical education school, community college, industrial or trade training organization, or labor organization; (4) a program which conforms to apprentice training programs developed or administered by an employer trade group or committee; or (5) an industry-sponsored or -administered program which is clearly identified and commonly recognized.

Terminates such credit after 2017.</summary>
</bill>
