<bill session="114" type="h" number="2441" updated="2015-08-08T06:39:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AVG Flying Tigers Congressional Gold Medal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To award a Congressional gold medal, collectively, to the 1st American Volunteer Group of the Chinese Air Force, also known as the AVG Flying Tigers, in recognition of their service to the nation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400041" joined="2015-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412557" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2015-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412409" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400313" joined="2015-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412426" joined="2015-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2015-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/2015--Introduced.
AVG Flying Tigers Congressional Gold Medal Act

This bill directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to arrange for the award on behalf of the Congress of a single gold medal to the 1st American Volunteer Group of the Chinese Air Force, also known as the AVG Flying Tigers, collectively in recognition of their service to the nation.

Following its award the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution where it will be displayed and made available for research.

It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal available for display elsewhere, particularly at other locations associated with the AVG Flying Tigers.</summary>
</bill>
