<bill session="114" type="h" number="2733" updated="2015-08-01T06:42:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Native Nations Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to take land into trust for certain Indian tribes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412500"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412645" joined="2015-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="s" number="1436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/2015--Introduced.
Nevada Native Nations Land Act

This bill declares that the United States holds in trust the following lands for the benefit of:

 the Fort McDermitt Paiute and Shoshone Tribe of the Fort McDermitt Indian Reservation, approximately 19,094 acres of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land; the Shoshone-Paiute Tribes of the Duck Valley Indian Reservation, approximately 82 acres of Forest Service land; the Summit Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 941 acres of BLM land; the Reno-Sparks Indian Colony, approximately 13,434 acres of BLM land; the Pyramid Lake Paiute Tribe, approximately 6,357 acres of BLM land; and the Duckwater Shoshone Tribe approximately 31,269 acres of BLM land. The lands held for such Tribes shall be part of their respective reservations.

Lands held in trust under this Act shall not be eligible for Class II and class III gaming.</summary>
</bill>
