<bill session="114" type="h" number="2751" updated="2015-08-08T06:42:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2015-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412403" joined="2015-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412519" joined="2015-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412626" joined="2015-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII24" subcommittee="Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs" name="House Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="246"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2015--Introduced.
Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act

 Establishes the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children in the Office of Tribal Justice of the Department of Justice.

Requires the President and Congress to appoint to the Commission individuals who have significant experience and expertise in Indian affairs and matters to be studied by the Commission.

Requires the Commission to establish a Native Advisory Committee consisting of representatives of Indian tribes from each region of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and a native Hawaiian.

Directs the Commission to study federal, state, local, and tribal programs that serve Native children and use the results of the study and analyses of existing federal data to: develop recommendations for goals and plans for federal policy relating to Native children informed by the development of accurate child well-being measures; recommend modifications and improvements to programs that serve Native children; recommend improvements to the collection of data regarding Native children and the programs that serve them; and identify models of successful federal, state, and tribal programs in the areas studied by the Commission. Requires the Commission to submit a report to the President, Congress, and the White House Council on Native American Affairs on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative and administrative action.</summary>
</bill>
