<bill session="114" type="h" number="2845" updated="2015-06-27T07:09:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGOA Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote access to benefits under the African Growth and Opportunity Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412404" joined="2015-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2015-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2015-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/19/2015--Introduced.
AGOA Enhancement Act of 2015

This bill directs the President establish the AGOA website for the collection and dissemination of information regarding the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) which shall include:

 information and technical assistance provided at U.S. Agency for International Development regional trade hubs, and a link to U.S. embassy websites located in eligible sub-Saharan African countries. The President should:

 implement policies to facilitate trans-boundary trade among eligible sub-Saharan African countries; provide training for business in such countries and government trade officials on accessing the benefits of AGOA and other trade preference programs; and provide capacity building for African entrepreneurs and trade associations, promoting product diversification and value-added processing, and helping businesses and institutions comply with U.S. counter-terrorism initiatives and policies. An eligible country that has entered into and has in effect a Millennium Challenge Compact under the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 may also enter into and have in effect at the same time not more than one additional Compact if:

 one or both of the Compacts are or will be for purposes of regional economic integration, increased regional trade, or cross-border collaborations; and the country is making considerable and demonstrable progress in implementing the terms of the existing Compact.</summary>
</bill>
