<bill session="114" type="h" number="2937" updated="2015-07-23T04:49:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cuban Military Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen support for the Cuban people and prohibit financial transactions with the Cuban military, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412625" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412469" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400636" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400077" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412651" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400086" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412621" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412526" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400108" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412472" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412661" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412645" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412553" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412550" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412284" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412649" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412290" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412468" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400276" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412662" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400285" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412302" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412431" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400626" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2015-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="412483" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412641" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412186" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400406" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412515" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412538" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412618" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400433" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412525" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412628" joined="2015-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="s" number="1489"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/2015--Introduced.
Cuban Military Transparency Act

This bill prohibits a U.S. person from engaging in any financial transaction with or transfer of funds to:

 the Ministry of the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Cuba or the Ministry of the Interior of Cuba (or any of their subdivisions); a senior member of such Ministries; any agency, instrumentality, or other entity that is more than 25% owned, or that is operated or controlled by, such a Ministry; or any individual or entity for the purpose of avoiding a prohibited financial transaction or transfer of funds that is for the benefit of that individual or entity. Such prohibitions shall not apply to:

 the sale to Cuba of agricultural commodities, medicines, and medical devices; a remittance to an immediate family member; assistance in furtherance of democracy-building efforts for Cuba; payments in furtherance of the lease agreement or other financial transactions necessary for maintenance and improvements of the military base at Guantanamo Bay; or customary and routine financial transactions necessary for the maintenance or regular duties of the U.S. Interests Section in Havana, including outreach to the pro-democracy opposition. A person that violates or attempts to violate such prohibitions shall be subject to specified penalties under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.

The Department of State rewards program under the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 shall include rewards for information leading to the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual responsible for or aiding in the February 1996 attack on the aircraft of U.S. persons in international waters by the Cuban military.

The Attorney General shall seek to coordinate with the International Criminal Police Organization (INTERPOL) to pursue the location and arrest of U.S. fugitives in Cuba, including current and former members of the Cuban military.</summary>
</bill>
