<bill session="114" type="h" number="2989" updated="2015-08-22T04:47:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">South Sudan Peace Promotion and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the warring parties of South Sudan to resolve their conflict peacefully, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400640" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400654" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="2015-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA16" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, Global Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2015--Introduced.
South Sudan Peace Promotion and Accountability Act of 2015

This bill states that Congress: (1) recognizes that there has been a failure of leadership in South Sudan that has left South Sudanese civilians in a protracted state of suffering, and that the United States stands in solidarity with the people of South Sudan as they call for peace; and (2) urges all parties in the conflict to cease all violence and work towards a negotiated settlement through diplomacy and reconciliation.

Specified sanctions imposed on individuals related to South Sudan shall remain in effect until the President certifies to Congress that such sanctions are no longer necessary.

Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit the President's authority to impose additional sanctions.

The President shall transmit to Congress a strategy to guide future U.S. engagement with South Sudan.</summary>
</bill>
