<bill session="114" type="h" number="3073" updated="2015-08-05T04:47:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sanctuary City All Funding Elimination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the receipt of Federal financial assistance by sanctuary cities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412477"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412622" joined="2015-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Border Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="3002"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/2015--Introduced.
Sanctuary City All Funding Elimination Act of 2015 or the SAFE Act of 2015

This bill prohibits a state or local government from receiving federal financial assistance if it restricts or prohibits a government entity or official from: (1) sending to or receiving from the responsible federal immigration agency information regarding an individual's citizenship or immigration status, or (2) maintaining or exchanging information about an individual's status.

 The prohibition shall be lifted when a state or local government submits a comprehensive plan to no longer restrict or prohibit such actions.</summary>
</bill>
