<bill session="114" type="h" number="757" updated="2015-08-01T04:50:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-02-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Korea Sanctions Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the enforcement of sanctions against the Government of North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400348"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412635" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412513" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412536" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412477" joined="2015-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412532" joined="2015-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412446" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400224" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412616" joined="2015-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412643" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2015-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400652" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400660" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="412489" joined="2015-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2015-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412417" joined="2015-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2015-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="412581" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412579" joined="2015-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412416" joined="2015-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Financial Services, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/2015--Introduced.
North Korea Sanctions Enforcement Act of 2015

This bill requires the President to investigate any credible information of sanctionable activities involving North Korea and to designate and apply sanctions with respect to any person (including entities) knowingly engaging in or contributing to activities in North Korea, through export or import, which involve weapons of mass destruction, significant arms or related materiel, significant luxury goods, money laundering, censorship, or human rights abuses.

The President shall exercise authorities under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act with respect to such persons and the government of North Korea.

The President also has discretionary authority to designate and apply sanctions to persons involved in certain other kinds of conduct.

Real or personal property will be subjected to civil forfeiture if it is involved in any attempted or actual violation of this Act, or which constitutes or is derived from proceeds traceable to such a violation.

The Secretary of the Treasury is required to:

 determine whether reasonable grounds exist for concluding that North Korea is a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern; and, if so, impose one or more special measures with respect to the jurisdiction of North Korea. The sense of Congress is declared about ensuring the consistent enforcement of United Nations Security Council resolutions and financial restrictions on North Korea.

A validated license is required for export to North Korea of any goods or technology subject to the Export Administration Regulations, which shall also be subject to a presumption of denial. Specified prohibitions and restrictions of the Arms Export Control Act shall be applied to any provision of munitions to North Korea regardless of whether it is designated as a state sponsor of terrorism.

The President must withhold assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to any country that provides lethal military equipment to, or receives it from, the government of North Korea.

U.S. government contracts with designated persons are forbidden.

The Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) shall require enhanced screening procedures to determine if physical inspections are warranted of any cargo bound for or landed in the United States that has been transported through a foreign seaport or airport whose inspections are deficient if there are reasonable grounds to believe that such cargo contains goods prohibited under this Act.

Seizure or forfeiture is also authorized for vessels or aircraft used to facilitate sanctionable activities.

Visas are denied to designated aliens, and the issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or DHS must revoke any visas or other entry documentation already issued to them.

Certain exemptions to designations and waivers of designations and sanctions will be allowed.

The President must report to Congress on:

 significant activities undermining cyber security conducted, or otherwise ordered or controlled, directly or indirectly, by the government of North Korea; and a detailed plan for making unrestricted, unmonitored, and inexpensive radio, Internet, and electronic mass communications available to the people of North Korea. The Secretary of State is required to report to Congress certain information on:

 each political prison camp in North Korea; and the identity of each person responsible for serious human rights abuses or censorship in North Korea, along with a description of those abuses or censorship. Circumstances for suspension or termination of sanctions are also specified.</summary>
</bill>
