<bill session="114" type="h" number="942" updated="2015-07-04T06:26:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Audit the Pentagon Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce by one-half of one percent the discretionary budget authority of any Federal agency for a fiscal year if the financial statement of the agency for the previous fiscal year does not receive a qualified or unqualified audit opinion by an external independent auditor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400237"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400052" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412533" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412215" joined="2015-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412585" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412259" joined="2015-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412239" joined="2015-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-12">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/12/2015--Introduced.
Audit the Pentagon Act of 2015 

This bill reduces discretionary spending by 0.5% for federal agencies that have either not submitted a financial statement for a fiscal year or have submitted a financial statement that has not received an unqualified or a qualified audit opinion by an independent external auditor.

The bill excludes specified Department of Defense (DOD) accounts for personnel and the Defense Health Program from the reductions.

The President may waive the reductions for any account by certifying that the cuts would harm national security or members of the Armed Forces who are in combat.

The bill establishes reporting requirements for the Office of Management and Budget and DOD.</summary>
</bill>
