<bill session="114" type="hj" number="8" updated="2015-02-07T06:22:54-05:00">
  <state datetime="2015-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States requiring that the Federal budget be balanced and that an increase in the Federal debt requires approval from a majority of the legislatures of the several States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412399"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412623" joined="2015-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU10" subcommittee="Constitution and Civil Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="sj" number="2"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/2015--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment 

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total outlays for a fiscal year from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year or 18% of the U.S. gross domestic product unless Congress authorizes the excess by a two-thirds vote of each chamber. The prohibition excludes outlays for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing.

The amendment requires a two-thirds vote of each chamber of Congress to levy a new tax, increase the rate of any tax, or increase the debt limit. Approval by a majority of the state legislatures is required to increase the federal debt.

The amendment provides any Member of Congress with standing and a cause of action to seek judicial enforcement of this amendment if authorized by a petition signed by one-third of the Members of either house of Congress. Courts are prohibited from ordering any increase in revenue to enforce this amendment.</summary>
</bill>
