<bill session="114" type="hr" number="183" updated="2015-06-11T04:46:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing support for the designation of the week of April 13, 2015, through April 17, 2015, as National Specialized Instructional Support Personnel Awareness Week.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412565" joined="2015-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2015-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="412211" joined="2015-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2015--Introduced.
Expresses support for the designation of National Specialized Instructional Support Personnel Awareness Week. Recognizes that such personnel implement evidence-based practices to improve student outcomes.

Commends the National Alliance of Specialized Instructional Support Personnel for its efforts to promote and improve the availability of specialized instructional support services.

Encourages: (1) policymakers to work together to raise awareness of the importance of such personnel in education reform efforts, and (2) experts to share best practices.

Urges: (1) the Department of Education to provide states and local educational agencies with guidance on effectively using such personnel to improve schools; and (2) the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to promote the involvement of such personnel in efforts to improve mental health, reduce drug use, and improve overall community safety.</summary>
</bill>
