<bill session="114" type="hr" number="227" updated="2015-06-25T04:46:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the murder of Boris Nemtsov, offering condolences to his family, friends, and colleagues, expressing solidarity with the people of Russia, and calling for an international investigation into this crime.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412470" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412236" joined="2015-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412272" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400646" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412435" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2015-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="412560" joined="2015-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2015-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA14" subcommittee="Europe, Eurasia, and Emerging Threats" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/2015--Introduced.
Condemns the murder of Boris Nemtsov and the climate of fear, hatred, and impunity that surrounds this and other political murders in Russia.

 Offers condolences to the family, friends, and colleagues of Boris Nemtsov.

Expresses solidarity with the people of Russia who are struggling against great odds to build a freer, more just, and prosperous future.

Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to support Russia's democratic opposition.

Calls on:

 the President to make greater use of the Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act, the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe to invoke the Moscow Mechanism and conduct an international investigation into Boris Nemtsov's murder, and the government of Russia to establish a Commission of Inquiry consistent with U.N. guidelines and to cooperate with any international investigation or assessment of Boris Nemtsov's murder.</summary>
</bill>
