<bill session="114" type="hr" number="270" updated="2015-07-08T04:47:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the Palestinian Authority's purported accession to the International Criminal Court for the purpose of initiating prosecutions against Israeli soldiers, citizens, officials, and leaders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412250" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412604" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412651" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400175" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412460" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412226" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412191" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2015-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412522" joined="2015-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2015--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of Congress that:

 the Palestinian Authority (PA) should withdraw its application for International Criminal Court (ICC) membership, cease attempts to initiate or encourage frivolous and politically motivated war-crimes prosecutions against Israelis via the ICC or any other international or national judicial body, and demonstrate its viability as a peace partner by returning to bilateral negotiations with Israel; the organs of the ICC should oppose the PA's politicization of international law by rescinding Palestinian membership in the ICC; the ICC should defer to Israeli jurisdiction and the Israeli military and civilian judicial systems in cases involving Israeli citizens; and the Administration should begin immediate consultations with Congress concerning Palestinian state-level membership in the ICC.</summary>
</bill>
