<bill session="114" type="hr" number="306" updated="2015-08-22T04:47:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the centennial of the wreck of the USS Memphis and encouraging the commemoration of such wreck with appropriate events and activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2015--Introduced.
Recognizes the centennial of the wreck of the USS Memphis and the memory of the 44 sailors who lost their lives, including three Medal of Honor recipients.

 Encourages the Department of State, through its Embassy in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic, to collaborate with appropriate entities of the Dominican Republic to commemorate this event.

 Encourages the Tennessee State Museum, the Naval History and Heritage Command, Naval Support Activity Mid-South, and the U.S. Naval Institute to collaborate in appropriate commemoration and public awareness events in the United States as well as in the Dominican Republic.</summary>
</bill>
