<bill session="114" type="s" number="1207" updated="2015-07-07T18:46:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Electric Systems Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible partnerships to provide for the transformation of the electric grid by the year 2030, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412200"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2015--Introduced.
Next Generation Electric Systems Act 

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a grants program for eligible partnerships to develop and implement projects related to achieving the transformation of the future electric grid by the year 2030 using a comprehensive approach to electric system design and architecture.

Eligible partnerships may include any institution of higher education, National Laboratory, representative of a state or local government, representative of an Indian tribe, federal power marketing administration, industry expert, or nonprofit industry trade association, but must include at least one electric utility (either investor-owned or publicly owned), technology provider, rural electric cooperative, Regional Transmission Organization, or Independent System Operator.

DOE must, when selecting eligible partnerships to receive grants, give priority to those proposing projects for which a cost-share is to be provided.</summary>
</bill>
