<bill session="114" type="s" number="1333" updated="2015-08-01T07:03:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Therapeutic Hemp Medical Access Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to exclude cannabidiol and cannabidiol-rich plants from the definition of marihuana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412406"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300002" joined="2015-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2015-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2015-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2015-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2015-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="1635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/2015--Introduced.
Therapeutic Hemp Medical Access Act of 2015

 Amends the Controlled Substances Act to exclude cannabidiol and cannabidiol-rich plants: (1) from the definition of "marihuana," and (2) from treatment as a controlled substance under such Act.

Defines: (1) "cannabidiol-rich plant" to mean the plant Cannabis sativa L. and any part of such plant with a tetrahydrocannabinol concentration of not more than 0.3% on a dry weight basis; (2) "cannabidiol" to mean the substance cannabidiol, as derived from a cannabidiol-rich plant; and (3) "tetrahydrocannabinol concentration" to mean the percent of the delta-9 tetrahydrocannabinol content per dry weight of any part of the plant Cannabis sativa L. or per volume of weight of marihuana product, or the combined percent of the delta-9 tetrahydrocannabinol and tetrahydrocannabinolic acid in any part of the plant Cannabis sativa L., regardless of moisture content.

Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to restrict any activities related to the use, production, or distribution of marihuana in a state in which such activities are legal under state law.</summary>
</bill>
