<bill session="114" type="s" number="1593" updated="2015-06-27T07:32:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Slush Fund Elimination Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to eliminate the offsetting accounts that are currently available for use by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412573"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="h" number="2825"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/2015--Introduced.
Immigration Slush Fund Elimination Act of 2015 

This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to provide that the following fees shall be miscellaneous receipts to be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury:

 asylum fees, nonimmigrant nurse fees, employer fees, additional employer fees, Department of State and Department of Homeland Security fraud prevention and detection fees, visa waiver program fees, temporary protected status fees, adjustment of status fees, administrative fines and penalties, the genealogy fee, the premium fee for employment-based petitions and applications, biometric entry and data system fees, and nonimmigrant foreign student fees. Authority for the visa waiver program travel promotion fee is extended through September 30, 2015.

 Fee disposition provisions are revised.

Fee revenues in all of the accounts under section 286 of INA, as of the day before enactment of this Act, shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury on the effective date provided for by this Act.

All of the accounts authorized under such section (including the Immigration User Fee Account and the Land Border Inspection Account), as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be terminated on such date.</summary>
</bill>
