<bill session="114" type="s" number="167" updated="2015-02-07T06:25:15-05:00">
  <state datetime="2015-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clay Hunt SAV Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for the conduct of annual evaluations of mental health care and suicide prevention programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to require a pilot program on loan repayment for psychiatrists who agree to serve in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400013" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412490" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400040" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400061" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412246" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300025" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300027" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412549" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412205" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300043" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400134" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412378" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412223" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412554" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412218" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412494" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2015-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400222" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412242" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412391" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400272" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300075" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412194" joined="2015-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300076" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300078" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2015-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300081" joined="2015-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300088" joined="2015-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412323" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2015-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="412665" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412244" joined="2015-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="412668" joined="2015-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2015-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="203"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/13/2015--Introduced.
Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act or the Clay Hunt SAV Act

 Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to arrange for an independent third party evaluation, to be conducted by September 30, 2018, and each fiscal year thereafter, of the VA's mental health care and suicide prevention programs.

 Directs the Secretary to survey the VA's websites and information resources to publish a website that serves as a centralized source to provide veterans with information regarding the VA's mental health care services.

 Requires the Secretary to carry out a three-year pilot program to repay the education loans relating to psychiatric medicine that are incurred by individuals who:

 are eligible to practice psychiatric medicine in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) or are enrolled in the final year of a residency program leading to a specialty qualification in psychiatric medicine; demonstrate a commitment to a long-term career as a psychiatrist in the VHA; and agree to a period of two or more years of obligated service with the VHA in the field of psychiatric medicine. Limits the loan repayment to no more than $30,000 for each year an individual performs such obligated service.

 Directs the Secretary to establish a three-year pilot program at not less than five Veterans Integrated Service Networks (VISNs) to assist veterans transitioning from active duty and to improve the access of veterans to mental health services. Requires the pilot program at each VISN to include: (1) a community oriented veteran peer support network carried out in partnership with an entity that has experience in peer support programs, and (2) a community outreach team for each medical center in such VISN.

Authorizes the Secretary to collaborate with nonprofit mental health organizations to prevent suicide among veterans. Requires the Secretary and any such organization to exchange training sessions and best practices.

Directs the Secretary to select a VA Director of Suicide Prevention Coordination to undertake any collaboration with nonprofit mental health organizations.

Extends for one year combat veterans' eligibility for VA hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care for illnesses that have not been medically proven to be attributable to their service, provided they: (1) were discharged or released from active duty between January 1, 2009, and January 1, 2011, and (2) did not enroll to receive such care during the five-year period of eligibility following their discharge or release.</summary>
</bill>
