<bill session="114" type="s" number="1725" updated="2015-07-14T12:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-07-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2016, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Graham. With written report No. 114-79.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-09" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="144">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="114" type="h" number="2772"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/2015--Introduced.
Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2016

 Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs.

Provides appropriations to the Department of State for Administration of Foreign Affairs, International Organizations, and International Commissions.

Provides appropriations for Related Agencies and Related Programs, including:

 the Broadcasting Board of Governors, the Asia Foundation, the U.S. Institute of Peace, the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund, the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Program, the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program, the East-West Center, and the National Endowment for Democracy. Provides appropriations for Other Commissions, including:

 the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad, the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom, the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, and the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission. Provides appropriations for the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID).

Provides appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance to:

 the President for Global Health Programs, Development Assistance, International Disaster Assistance, and the Economic Support Fund: the Department of State for Migration and Refugee Assistance; Independent Agencies, including the Peace Corps, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Inter-American Foundation, and the U.S. African Development Foundation; and the Department of the Treasury for International Affairs Technical Assistance. Provides appropriations to the Department of State and the President for International Security Assistance.

Provides appropriations for International Financial Institutions, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, and the Overseas Private Investment Corporation.

Provides appropriations for Overseas Contingency Operations.

Provides appropriations to the President for Humanitarian Emergency Response, including International Disaster Assistance and Migration and Refugee Assistance. Designates the funds as emergency spending.

Provides appropriations for Other Matters and Multilateral Assistance, including the International Monetary Fund.

Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations. Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
</bill>
