<bill session="114" type="s" number="565" updated="2015-07-04T06:51:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-06-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the operation and maintenance costs associated with the Federal fleet by encouraging the use of remanufactured parts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412667" joined="2015-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="412464" joined="2015-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="2015-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-03-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 114-59.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-05-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="101">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 101.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-06-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4168" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4168" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16T12:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="h" number="1613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/2015--Passed Senate without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)

Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015

(Sec. 3) Defines "remanufactured vehicle component" as a vehicle component (including an engine, transmission, alternator, starter, turbocharger, steering, or suspension component) that has been returned to same-as-new, or better, condition and performance by a standardized industrial process that incorporates technical specifications (including engineering, quality, and testing standards) to yield fully warranted products.

(Sec. 4) Directs the head of each federal agency to: (1) encourage the use of remanufactured vehicle components to maintain federal vehicles if using such components reduces the cost of maintaining such vehicles while maintaining quality; and (2) not encourage the use of remanufactured vehicle components if using such components does not reduce the cost of maintenance, lowers the quality of vehicle performance,&#160;or delays the return to service of a vehicle.</summary>
</bill>
