<bill session="114" type="s" number="779" updated="2015-08-05T04:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-07-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Science and Technology Research Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for Federal agencies to develop public access policies relating to research conducted by employees of that agency or from funds administered by that agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300027"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412496" joined="2015-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412507" joined="2015-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="2015-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1630-1631" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-07-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="h" number="1477"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2015--Introduced.
Fair Access to Science and Technology Research Act of 2015

Requires each federal agency with extramural research expenditures of over $100 million to develop a federal research public access policy that is consistent with, and that advances, the purposes of the agency and that follows common procedures for the collection and depositing of research papers.

Makes each federal research public access policy applicable to: (1) researchers employed by the federal agency whose works remain in the public domain, and (2) researchers funded by the agency. Specifies exclusions.

Requires each federal agency to submit an annual report on its federal research public access policy to specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
