<bill session="114" type="s" number="818" updated="2015-08-01T06:58:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412325" joined="2015-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1664"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1666-1667" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="114" type="h" number="3212"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/2015--Introduced.
Authorizes the Department of the Interior to accept title to any additional number of acres of real property located within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon (comprising land within the political boundaries of Polk and Yamhill Counties, Oregon), if such real property is conveyed or otherwise transferred to the United States by or on behalf of the Tribe.

States that: (1) Interior shall treat applications to take land into trust within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation as an on-reservation trust acquisition; (2) the real property taken into trust is not to be eligible, or used, for certain gaming, except for real property within two miles of a specified gaming facility; and (3) all real property taken into trust within those boundaries after September 9, 1988, shall be part of the Tribe's reservation.</summary>
</bill>
