<bill session="114" type="s" number="881" updated="2015-05-02T06:47:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Regulatory Review Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that Federal financial regulators perform a comprehensive review of regulations to identify outdated or otherwise unnecessary regulatory requirements imposed on financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300030"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/2015--Introduced.
Comprehensive Regulatory Review Act of 2015

This bill amends the Economic Growth and Regulatory Paperwork Reduction Act of 1996 to specify the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, and the National Credit Union Administration Board as the federal agency representatives on the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council which are required, along with the Council, to review all Council-prescribed regulations at least once every 10 years in order to identify outdated or unnecessary regulatory requirements imposed upon financial institutions (currently, only insured depository institutions).

 This decennial review shall include all regulations issued pursuant to the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act.</summary>
</bill>
