<bill session="114" type="s" number="957" updated="2015-06-26T04:49:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="2015-04-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Entrepreneurship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase access to capital for veteran entrepreneurs to help create jobs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="412323"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="412493" joined="2015-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="412330" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300018" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412390" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412556" joined="2015-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="412200" joined="2015-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="412545" joined="2015-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="412305" joined="2015-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Vitter without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-06-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="105">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/2015--Reported to Senate without amendment.
(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Veterans Entrepreneurship Act

(Sec. 3) Amends the Small Business Act to prohibit the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) from assessing a guarantee fee in connection with a loan made under the SBA Express Program to a veteran or spouse of a veteran on or after October 1, 2015.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator to report to Congress on: (1) the feasibility of providing financial planning and counseling to owners of small business concerns who are members of a reserve component prior to deployment; (2) the level of outreach to and consultation with female veterans by women's business centers and veterans business outreach centers; and (3) the Military Reservists Economic Injury Disaster Loan Program, which shall include a discussion of SBA outreach efforts to increase participation, the number of loans made, and an analysis of the effectiveness of, and recommendations for improving, the Program.</summary>
</bill>
